<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ks-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-1130"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-1130"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ks-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ks"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-1130/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-1130/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ks-legislature"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-1130/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-1130/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ks-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ks/legislature" showAs="Kansas Legislature"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_79">
        <num>Chapter 79</num>
        <heading>Taxation</heading>
        <article eId="chp_79__art_11">
          <num>Article 11</num>
          <heading>Banks, Banking Businesses, Trust Companies and Savings and Loan Associations</heading>
          <section eId="sec_79_1130">
            <num>79-1130</num>
            <heading>Same; receipts factor defined and described</heading>
            <content>
              <p>79-1130. Same; receipts factor defined and described. (a) General. The receipts factor is a fraction, the numerator of which is the receipts of the taxpayer in this state during the taxable year and the denominator of which is the receipts of the taxpayer within and without this state during the taxable year. The method of calculating receipts for purposes of the denominator is the same as the method used in determining receipts for purposes of the numerator. The receipts factor shall include only those receipts described herein which constitute business income and are included in the computation of the apportionable income base for the taxable year. (b) Receipts from the lease of real property. The numerator of the receipts factor includes receipts from the lease or rental of real property owned by the taxpayer if the property is located within this state or receipts from the sublease of real property if the property is located within this state. (c) Receipts from the lease of tangible personal property. (1) Except as described in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the numerator of the receipts factor includes receipts from the lease or rental of tangible personal property owned by the taxpayer if the property is located within this state when it is first placed in service by the lessee. (2) Receipts from the lease or rental of transportation property owned by the taxpayer are included in the numerator of the receipts factor to the extent that the property is used in this state. The extent an aircraft will be deemed to be used in this state and the amount of receipts that is to be included in the numerator of this state's receipts factor is determined by multiplying all the receipts from the lease or rental of the aircraft by a fraction, the numerator of which is the number of landings of the aircraft in this state and the denominator of which is the total number of landings of the aircraft. If the extent of the use of any transportation property within this state cannot be determined, then the property will be deemed to be used wholly in the state in which the property has its principal base of operations. A motor vehicle will be deemed to be used wholly in the state in which it is registered. (d) Interest from loans secured by real property. (1) The numerator of the receipts factor includes interest and fees or penalties in the nature of interest from loans secured by real property if the property is located within this state. If the property is located both within this state and one or more other states, the receipts described in this subsection are included in the numerator of the receipts factor if more than 50% of the fair market value of the real property is located within this state. If more than 50% of the fair market value of the real property is not located within any one state, then the receipts described in this subsection shall be included in the numerator of the receipts factor if the borrower is located in this state. (2) The determination of whether the real property securing a loan is located within this state shall be made as of the time the original agreement was made and any and all subsequent substitutions of collateral shall be disregarded. (e) Interest from loans not secured by real property. The numerator of the receipts factor includes interest and fees or penalties in the nature of interest from loans not secured by real property if the borrower is located in this state. (f) Net gains from the sale of loans. The numerator of the receipts factor includes net gains from the sale of loans. Net gains from the sale of loans includes income recorded under the coupon stripping rules of section 1286 of the internal revenue code. (1) The amount of net gains, but not less than zero, from the sale of loans secured by real property included in the numerator is determined by multiplying such net gains by a fraction the numerator of which is the amount included in the numerator of the receipts factor pursuant to subsection (d) and the denominator of which is the total amount of interest and fees or penalties in the nature of interest from loans secured by real property. (2) The amount of net gains, but not less than zero, from the sale of loans not secured by real property included in the numerator is determined by multiplying such net gains by a fraction the numerator of which is the amount included in the numerator of the receipts factor pursuant to subsection (e) and the denominator of which is the total amount of interest and fees or penalties in the nature of interest from loans not secured by real property. (g) Receipts from credit card receivables. The numerator of the receipts factor includes interest and fees or penalties in the nature of interest from credit card receivables and receipts from fees charged to card holders, such as annual fees, if the billing address of the card holder is in this state. (h) Net gains from the sale of credit card receivables. The numerator of the receipts factor includes net gains, but not less than zero, from the sale of credit card receivables multiplied by a fraction, the numerator of which is the amount included in the numerator of the receipts factor pursuant to subsection (g) and the denominator of which is the taxpayer's total amount of interest and fees or penalties in the nature of interest from credit card receivables and fees charged to card holders. (i) Credit card issuer's reimbursement fees. The numerator of the receipts factor includes all credit card issuer's reimbursement fees multiplied by a fraction, the numerator of which is the amount included in the numerator of the receipts factor pursuant to subsection (g) and the denominator of which is the taxpayer's total amount of interest and fees or penalties in the nature of interest from credit card receivables and fees charged to card holders. (j) Receipts from merchant discount. The numerator of the receipts factor includes receipts from merchant discount if the commercial domicile of the merchant is in this state. Such receipts shall be computed net of any cardholder charge backs, but shall not be reduced by any interchange transaction fees or by any issuer's reimbursement fees paid to another for charges made by its card holders. (k) Loan servicing fees. (1) (A) The numerator of the receipts factor includes loan servicing fees derived from loans secured by real property multiplied by a fraction the numerator of which is the amount included in the numerator of the receipts factor pursuant to subsection (d) and the denominator of which is the total amount of interest and fees or penalties in the nature of interest from loans secured by real property. (B) The numerator of the receipts factor includes loan servicing fees derived from loans not secured by real property multiplied by a fraction the numerator of which is the amount included in the numerator of the receipts factor pursuant to subsection (e) and the denominator of which is the total amount of interest and fees or penalties in the nature of interest from loans not secured by real property. (2) In circumstances in which the taxpayer receives loan servicing fees for servicing either the secured or the unsecured loans of another, the numerator of the receipts factor shall include such fees if the borrower is located in this state. (l) Receipts from services. The numerator of the receipts factor includes receipts from services not otherwise apportioned under this section if the service is performed in this state. If the service is performed both within and without this state, the numerator of the receipts factor includes receipts from services not otherwise apportioned under this section, if a greater proportion of the income-producing activity is performed in this state based on cost of performance. (m) Receipts from investment assets and activities and trading assets and activities. (1) Interest, dividends, net gains, but not less than zero, and other income from investment assets and activities and from trading assets and activities shall be included in the receipts factor. Investment assets and activities and trading assets and activities include but are not limited to: Investment securities; trading account assets; federal funds; securities purchased and sold under agreements to resell or repurchase; options; futures contracts; forward contracts; notional principal contracts such as swaps; equities; and foreign currency transactions. With respect to the investment and trading assets and activities described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of this paragraph, the receipts factor shall include the amounts described in such subparagraphs. (A) The receipts factor shall include the amount by which interest from federal funds sold and securities purchased under resale agreements exceeds interest expense on federal funds purchased and securities sold under repurchase agreements. (B) The receipts factor shall include the amount by which interest, dividends, gains and other income from trading assets and activities, including but not limited to assets and activities in the matched book, in the arbitrage book, and foreign currency transactions, exceed amounts paid in lieu of interest, amounts paid in lieu of dividends, and losses from such assets and activities. (2) The numerator of the receipts factor includes interest, dividends, net gains, but not less than zero, and other income from investment assets and activities and from trading assets and activities described in paragraph (1) of this subsection that are attributable to this state. (A) The amount of interest, dividends, net gains, but not less than zero, and other income from investment assets and activities in the investment account to be attributed to this state and included in the numerator is determined by multiplying all such income from such assets and activities by a fraction, the numerator of which is the average value of such assets which are properly assigned to a regular place of business of the taxpayer within this state and the denominator of which is the average value of all such assets. (B) The amount of interest from federal funds sold and purchased and from securities purchased under resale agreements and securities sold under repurchase agreements attributable to this state and included in the numerator is determined by multiplying the amount described in subparagraph (A) of paragraph (1) of this subsection from such funds and such securities by a fraction, the numerator of which is the average value of federal funds sold and securities purchased under agreements to resell which are properly assigned to a regular place of business of the taxpayer within this state and the denominator of which is the average value of all such funds and such securities. (C) The amount of interest, dividends, gains and other income from trading assets and activities, including but not limited to assets and activities in the matched book, in the arbitrage book and foreign currency transactions, but excluding amounts described in subparagraphs (A) or (B) of this paragraph, attributable to this state and included in the numerator is determined by multiplying the amount described in subparagraph (B) of paragraph (1) of this subsection by a fraction, the numerator of which is the average value of such training assets which are properly assigned to a regular place of business of the taxpayer within this state and the denominator of which is the average value of all such assets. (D) For purposes of this paragraph, average value shall be determined using the rules for determining the average value of tangible personal property set forth in subsections (c) and (d) of K.S.A. 79-1131. (3) In lieu of using the method set forth in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the secretary of revenue may permit or require in order to fairly represent the business activity of the taxpayer in this state, the use of the method set forth in this paragraph. (A) The amount of interest, dividends, net gain, but not less than zero, and other income from investment assets and activities in the investment account to be attributed to this state and included in the numerator is determined by multiplying all such income from such assets and activities by a fraction, the numerator of which is the gross income from such assets and activities which are properly assigned to a regular place of business of the taxpayer within this state and the denominator of which is the gross income from all such assets and activities. (B) The amount of interest from federal funds sold and purchased and from securities purchased under resale agreements and securities sold under repurchase agreements attributable to this state and included in the numerator is determined by multiplying the amount described in subparagraph (A) of paragraph (1) of this subsection from such funds and such securities by a fraction, the numerator of which is the gross income from such funds and such securities which are properly assigned to a regular place of business of the taxpayer within this state and the denominator of which is the gross income from all such funds and such securities. (C) The amount of interest, dividends, gains and other income from trading assets and activities, including but not limited to assets and activities in the matched book, in the arbitrage book and foreign currency transactions, but excluding amounts described in subparagraphs (A) or (B) of this paragraph, attributable to this state and included in the numerator is determined by multiplying the amount described in subparagraph (B) of paragraph (1) of this subsection by a fraction, the numerator of which is the gross income from such trading assets and activities which are properly assigned to a regular place of business of the taxpayer within this state and the denominator of which is the gross income from all such assets and activities. (4) If the taxpayer elects or is required by the secretary of revenue to use the method set forth in paragraph (3) of this subsection, it shall use this method on all subsequent returns unless the taxpayer receives prior permission from the secretary of revenue to use, or the secretary of revenue requires a different method. (5) The taxpayer shall have the burden of proving that an investment asset or activity or trading asset or activity was properly assigned to a regular place of business outside of this state by demonstrating that the day-to-day decisions regarding the asset or activity occurred at a regular place of business outside this state. Where the day-to-day decisions regarding an investment asset or activity or trading asset or activity occur at more than one regular place of business and one such regular place of business is in this state and one such regular place of business is outside this state, such asset or activity shall be considered to be located at the regular place of business of the taxpayer where the investment or trading policies or guidelines with respect to the asset or activity are established. Unless the taxpayer demonstrates to the contrary, such policies and guidelines shall be presumed to be established at the commercial domicile of the taxpayer. (n) Other receipts. To the extent not inconsistent with this act, the numerator of the receipts factor includes other receipts pursuant to the rules set forth in K.S.A. 79-3286, 79-3287, and 79-3288, and amendments thereto. (o) Attribution of certain receipts to commercial domicile. All receipts which would be assigned under this section to a state in which the taxpayer is not taxable shall be included in the numerator of the receipts factor, if the taxpayer's commercial domicile is in this state.</p>
            </content>
            <subsection eId="79_1130__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>General. The receipts factor is a fraction, the numerator of which is the receipts of the taxpayer in this state during the taxable year and the denominator of which is the receipts of the taxpayer within and without this state during the taxable year. The method of calculating receipts for purposes of the denominator is the same as the method used in determining receipts for purposes of the numerator. The receipts factor shall include only those receipts described herein which constitute business income and are included in the computation of the apportionable income base for the taxable year.</p>
              </content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_1130__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Receipts from the lease of real property. The numerator of the receipts factor includes receipts from the lease or rental of real property owned by the taxpayer if the property is located within this state or receipts from the sublease of real property if the property is located within this state.</p>
              </content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_1130__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Receipts from the lease of tangible personal property.</p>
              </content>
              <paragraph eId="79_1130__subsec_c__para_1">
                <num>(1)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Except as described in paragraph</p>
                </content>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph eId="79_1130__subsec_c__para_2">
                <num>(2)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>of this subsection, the numerator of the receipts factor includes receipts from the lease or rental of tangible personal property owned by the taxpayer if the property is located within this state when it is first placed in service by the lessee.</p>
                </content>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph eId="79_1130__subsec_c__para_2">
                <num>(2)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Receipts from the lease or rental of transportation property owned by the taxpayer are included in the numerator of the receipts factor to the extent that the property is used in this state. The extent an aircraft will be deemed to be used in this state and the amount of receipts that is to be included in the numerator of this state's receipts factor is determined by multiplying all the receipts from the lease or rental of the aircraft by a fraction, the numerator of which is the number of landings of the aircraft in this state and the denominator of which is the total number of landings of the aircraft. If the extent of the use of any transportation property within this state cannot be determined, then the property will be deemed to be used wholly in the state in which the property has its principal base of operations. A motor vehicle will be deemed to be used wholly in the state in which it is registered.</p>
                </content>
              </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_1130__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Interest from loans secured by real property.</p>
              </content>
              <paragraph eId="79_1130__subsec_d__para_1">
                <num>(1)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>The numerator of the receipts factor includes interest and fees or penalties in the nature of interest from loans secured by real property if the property is located within this state. If the property is located both within this state and one or more other states, the receipts described in this subsection are included in the numerator of the receipts factor if more than 50% of the fair market value of the real property is located within this state. If more than 50% of the fair market value of the real property is not located within any one state, then the receipts described in this subsection shall be included in the numerator of the receipts factor if the borrower is located in this state.</p>
                </content>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph eId="79_1130__subsec_d__para_2">
                <num>(2)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>The determination of whether the real property securing a loan is located within this state shall be made as of the time the original agreement was made and any and all subsequent substitutions of collateral shall be disregarded.</p>
                </content>
              </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_1130__subsec_e">
              <num>(e)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Interest from loans not secured by real property. The numerator of the receipts factor includes interest and fees or penalties in the nature of interest from loans not secured by real property if the borrower is located in this state.</p>
              </content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_1130__subsec_f">
              <num>(f)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Net gains from the sale of loans. The numerator of the receipts factor includes net gains from the sale of loans. Net gains from the sale of loans includes income recorded under the coupon stripping rules of section 1286 of the internal revenue code.</p>
              </content>
              <paragraph eId="79_1130__subsec_f__para_1">
                <num>(1)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>The amount of net gains, but not less than zero, from the sale of loans secured by real property included in the numerator is determined by multiplying such net gains by a fraction the numerator of which is the amount included in the numerator of the receipts factor pursuant to subsection</p>
                </content>
              </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_1130__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>and the denominator of which is the total amount of interest and fees or penalties in the nature of interest from loans secured by real property.</p>
              </content>
              <paragraph eId="79_1130__subsec_d__para_2">
                <num>(2)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>The amount of net gains, but not less than zero, from the sale of loans not secured by real property included in the numerator is determined by multiplying such net gains by a fraction the numerator of which is the amount included in the numerator of the receipts factor pursuant to subsection</p>
                </content>
              </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_1130__subsec_e">
              <num>(e)</num>
              <content>
                <p>and the denominator of which is the total amount of interest and fees or penalties in the nature of interest from loans not secured by real property.</p>
              </content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_1130__subsec_g">
              <num>(g)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Receipts from credit card receivables. The numerator of the receipts factor includes interest and fees or penalties in the nature of interest from credit card receivables and receipts from fees charged to card holders, such as annual fees, if the billing address of the card holder is in this state.</p>
              </content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_1130__subsec_h">
              <num>(h)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Net gains from the sale of credit card receivables. The numerator of the receipts factor includes net gains, but not less than zero, from the sale of credit card receivables multiplied by a fraction, the numerator of which is the amount included in the numerator of the receipts factor pursuant to subsection</p>
              </content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_1130__subsec_g">
              <num>(g)</num>
              <content>
                <p>and the denominator of which is the taxpayer's total amount of interest and fees or penalties in the nature of interest from credit card receivables and fees charged to card holders.</p>
              </content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_1130__subsec_i">
              <num>(i)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Credit card issuer's reimbursement fees. The numerator of the receipts factor includes all credit card issuer's reimbursement fees multiplied by a fraction, the numerator of which is the amount included in the numerator of the receipts factor pursuant to subsection</p>
              </content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_1130__subsec_g">
              <num>(g)</num>
              <content>
                <p>and the denominator of which is the taxpayer's total amount of interest and fees or penalties in the nature of interest from credit card receivables and fees charged to card holders.</p>
              </content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_1130__subsec_j">
              <num>(j)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Receipts from merchant discount. The numerator of the receipts factor includes receipts from merchant discount if the commercial domicile of the merchant is in this state. Such receipts shall be computed net of any cardholder charge backs, but shall not be reduced by any interchange transaction fees or by any issuer's reimbursement fees paid to another for charges made by its card holders.</p>
              </content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_1130__subsec_k">
              <num>(k)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Loan servicing fees.</p>
              </content>
              <paragraph eId="79_1130__subsec_k__para_1">
                <num>(1)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>(A) The numerator of the receipts factor includes loan servicing fees derived from loans secured by real property multiplied by a fraction the numerator of which is the amount included in the numerator of the receipts factor pursuant to subsection</p>
                </content>
              </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_1130__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>and the denominator of which is the total amount of interest and fees or penalties in the nature of interest from loans secured by real property. (B) The numerator of the receipts factor includes loan servicing fees derived from loans not secured by real property multiplied by a fraction the numerator of which is the amount included in the numerator of the receipts factor pursuant to subsection</p>
              </content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_1130__subsec_e">
              <num>(e)</num>
              <content>
                <p>and the denominator of which is the total amount of interest and fees or penalties in the nature of interest from loans not secured by real property.</p>
              </content>
              <paragraph eId="79_1130__subsec_e__para_2">
                <num>(2)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>In circumstances in which the taxpayer receives loan servicing fees for servicing either the secured or the unsecured loans of another, the numerator of the receipts factor shall include such fees if the borrower is located in this state.</p>
                </content>
              </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_1130__subsec_l">
              <num>(l)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Receipts from services. The numerator of the receipts factor includes receipts from services not otherwise apportioned under this section if the service is performed in this state. If the service is performed both within and without this state, the numerator of the receipts factor includes receipts from services not otherwise apportioned under this section, if a greater proportion of the income-producing activity is performed in this state based on cost of performance.</p>
              </content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_1130__subsec_m">
              <num>(m)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Receipts from investment assets and activities and trading assets and activities.</p>
              </content>
              <paragraph eId="79_1130__subsec_m__para_1">
                <num>(1)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Interest, dividends, net gains, but not less than zero, and other income from investment assets and activities and from trading assets and activities shall be included in the receipts factor. Investment assets and activities and trading assets and activities include but are not limited to: Investment securities; trading account assets; federal funds; securities purchased and sold under agreements to resell or repurchase; options; futures contracts; forward contracts; notional principal contracts such as swaps; equities; and foreign currency transactions. With respect to the investment and trading assets and activities described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of this paragraph, the receipts factor shall include the amounts described in such subparagraphs. (A) The receipts factor shall include the amount by which interest from federal funds sold and securities purchased under resale agreements exceeds interest expense on federal funds purchased and securities sold under repurchase agreements. (B) The receipts factor shall include the amount by which interest, dividends, gains and other income from trading assets and activities, including but not limited to assets and activities in the matched book, in the arbitrage book, and foreign currency transactions, exceed amounts paid in lieu of interest, amounts paid in lieu of dividends, and losses from such assets and activities.</p>
                </content>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph eId="79_1130__subsec_m__para_2">
                <num>(2)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>The numerator of the receipts factor includes interest, dividends, net gains, but not less than zero, and other income from investment assets and activities and from trading assets and activities described in paragraph</p>
                </content>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph eId="79_1130__subsec_m__para_1">
                <num>(1)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>of this subsection that are attributable to this state. (A) The amount of interest, dividends, net gains, but not less than zero, and other income from investment assets and activities in the investment account to be attributed to this state and included in the numerator is determined by multiplying all such income from such assets and activities by a fraction, the numerator of which is the average value of such assets which are properly assigned to a regular place of business of the taxpayer within this state and the denominator of which is the average value of all such assets. (B) The amount of interest from federal funds sold and purchased and from securities purchased under resale agreements and securities sold under repurchase agreements attributable to this state and included in the numerator is determined by multiplying the amount described in subparagraph (A) of paragraph</p>
                </content>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph eId="79_1130__subsec_m__para_1">
                <num>(1)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>of this subsection from such funds and such securities by a fraction, the numerator of which is the average value of federal funds sold and securities purchased under agreements to resell which are properly assigned to a regular place of business of the taxpayer within this state and the denominator of which is the average value of all such funds and such securities. (C) The amount of interest, dividends, gains and other income from trading assets and activities, including but not limited to assets and activities in the matched book, in the arbitrage book and foreign currency transactions, but excluding amounts described in subparagraphs (A) or (B) of this paragraph, attributable to this state and included in the numerator is determined by multiplying the amount described in subparagraph (B) of paragraph</p>
                </content>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph eId="79_1130__subsec_m__para_1">
                <num>(1)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>of this subsection by a fraction, the numerator of which is the average value of such training assets which are properly assigned to a regular place of business of the taxpayer within this state and the denominator of which is the average value of all such assets. (D) For purposes of this paragraph, average value shall be determined using the rules for determining the average value of tangible personal property set forth in subsections</p>
                </content>
              </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_1130__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>and</p>
              </content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_1130__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of K.S.A. 79-1131.</p>
              </content>
              <paragraph eId="79_1130__subsec_d__para_3">
                <num>(3)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>In lieu of using the method set forth in paragraph</p>
                </content>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph eId="79_1130__subsec_d__para_2">
                <num>(2)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>of this subsection, the secretary of revenue may permit or require in order to fairly represent the business activity of the taxpayer in this state, the use of the method set forth in this paragraph. (A) The amount of interest, dividends, net gain, but not less than zero, and other income from investment assets and activities in the investment account to be attributed to this state and included in the numerator is determined by multiplying all such income from such assets and activities by a fraction, the numerator of which is the gross income from such assets and activities which are properly assigned to a regular place of business of the taxpayer within this state and the denominator of which is the gross income from all such assets and activities. (B) The amount of interest from federal funds sold and purchased and from securities purchased under resale agreements and securities sold under repurchase agreements attributable to this state and included in the numerator is determined by multiplying the amount described in subparagraph (A) of paragraph</p>
                </content>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph eId="79_1130__subsec_d__para_1">
                <num>(1)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>of this subsection from such funds and such securities by a fraction, the numerator of which is the gross income from such funds and such securities which are properly assigned to a regular place of business of the taxpayer within this state and the denominator of which is the gross income from all such funds and such securities. (C) The amount of interest, dividends, gains and other income from trading assets and activities, including but not limited to assets and activities in the matched book, in the arbitrage book and foreign currency transactions, but excluding amounts described in subparagraphs (A) or (B) of this paragraph, attributable to this state and included in the numerator is determined by multiplying the amount described in subparagraph (B) of paragraph</p>
                </content>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph eId="79_1130__subsec_d__para_1">
                <num>(1)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>of this subsection by a fraction, the numerator of which is the gross income from such trading assets and activities which are properly assigned to a regular place of business of the taxpayer within this state and the denominator of which is the gross income from all such assets and activities.</p>
                </content>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph eId="79_1130__subsec_d__para_4">
                <num>(4)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>If the taxpayer elects or is required by the secretary of revenue to use the method set forth in paragraph</p>
                </content>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph eId="79_1130__subsec_d__para_3">
                <num>(3)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>of this subsection, it shall use this method on all subsequent returns unless the taxpayer receives prior permission from the secretary of revenue to use, or the secretary of revenue requires a different method.</p>
                </content>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph eId="79_1130__subsec_d__para_5">
                <num>(5)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>The taxpayer shall have the burden of proving that an investment asset or activity or trading asset or activity was properly assigned to a regular place of business outside of this state by demonstrating that the day-to-day decisions regarding the asset or activity occurred at a regular place of business outside this state. Where the day-to-day decisions regarding an investment asset or activity or trading asset or activity occur at more than one regular place of business and one such regular place of business is in this state and one such regular place of business is outside this state, such asset or activity shall be considered to be located at the regular place of business of the taxpayer where the investment or trading policies or guidelines with respect to the asset or activity are established. Unless the taxpayer demonstrates to the contrary, such policies and guidelines shall be presumed to be established at the commercial domicile of the taxpayer.</p>
                </content>
              </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_1130__subsec_n">
              <num>(n)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Other receipts. To the extent not inconsistent with this act, the numerator of the receipts factor includes other receipts pursuant to the rules set forth in K.S.A. 79-3286, 79-3287, and 79-3288, and amendments thereto.</p>
              </content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_1130__subsec_o">
              <num>(o)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Attribution of certain receipts to commercial domicile. All receipts which would be assigned under this section to a state in which the taxpayer is not taxable shall be included in the numerator of the receipts factor, if the taxpayer's commercial domicile is in this state.</p>
              </content>
            </subsection>
          </section>
        </article>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
