<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ks-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-3615"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-3615"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ks-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ks"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-3615/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-3615/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ks-legislature"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-3615/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-3615/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ks-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ks/legislature" showAs="Kansas Legislature"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_79">
        <num>Chapter 79</num>
        <heading>Taxation</heading>
        <article eId="chp_79__art_36">
          <num>Article 36</num>
          <heading>Kansas Retailers' Sales Tax</heading>
          <section eId="sec_79_3615">
            <num>79-3615</num>
            <heading>Interest and penalties</heading>
            <content>
              <p>79-3615. Interest and penalties. (a) If any taxpayer shall fail to pay the tax required under this act at the time required by or under the provisions of this act, there shall be added to the unpaid balance of the tax, interest at the rate per month prescribed by subsection (a) of K.S.A. 79-2968, and amendments thereto, from the date the tax was due until paid. (b) For all taxable years ending prior to January 1, 2002, if any taxpayer due to negligence or intentional disregard fails to file a return or pay the tax due at the time required by or under the provisions of this act, there shall be added to the tax a penalty in an amount equal to 10% of the unpaid balance of tax due. (c) For all taxable years ending prior to January 1, 2002, if any person fails to make a return, or to pay any tax, within six months from the date the return or tax was due, except in the case of an extension of time granted by the secretary of revenue or the secretary's designee, there shall be added to the tax due a penalty equal to 25% of the unpaid balance of such tax due. Notwithstanding the foregoing, in the event an assessment is issued following a field audit for any period for which a return was filed by the taxpayer and all of the tax was paid pursuant to such return, a penalty shall be imposed for the period included in the assessment in the amount of 10% of the unpaid balance of tax due shown in the notice of assessment. If after review of a return for any period included in the assessment, the secretary or secretary's designee determines that the underpayment of tax was due to the failure of the taxpayer to make a reasonable attempt to comply with the provisions of this act, such penalty shall be imposed for the period included in the assessment in the amount of 25% of the unpaid balance of tax due. (d) For all taxable years ending after December 31, 2001, if any taxpayer fails to file a return or pay the tax if one is due, at the time required by or under the provisions of this act, there shall be added to the tax an additional amount equal to 1% of the unpaid balance of the tax due for each month or fraction thereof during which such failure continues, not exceeding 24% in the aggregate, plus interest at the rate prescribed by subsection (a) of K.S.A. 79-2968, and amendments thereto, from the date the tax was due until paid. Notwithstanding the foregoing, in the event an assessment is issued following a field audit for any period for which a return was filed by the taxpayer and all of the tax was paid pursuant to such return, a penalty shall be imposed for the period included in the assessment in an amount of 1% per month not exceeding 10% of the unpaid balance of tax due shown in the notice of assessment. If after review of a return for any period included in the assessment, the secretary or secretary's designee determines that the underpayment of tax was due to the failure of the taxpayer to make a reasonable attempt to comply with the provisions of this act, such penalty shall be imposed for the period included in the assessment in the amount of 25% of the unpaid balance of tax due. (e) If any taxpayer, with fraudulent intent, fails to pay any tax or make, render or sign any return, or to supply any information, within the time required by or under the provisions of this act, there shall be added to the tax a penalty in an amount equal to 50% of the unpaid balance of tax due. (f) Penalty or interest applied under the provisions of subsections (a) and (d) shall be in addition to the penalty added under any other provisions of this section, but the provisions of subsections (b) and (c) shall be mutually exclusive of each other. (g) Whenever the secretary or the secretary's designee determines that the failure of the taxpayer to comply with the provisions of subsections (a), (b), (c) and (d) of this section was due to reasonable causes, the secretary or the secretary's designee may waive or reduce any of the penalties and may reduce the interest rate to the underpayment rate prescribed and determined for the applicable period under section 6621 of the federal internal revenue code as in effect on January 1, 1994, upon making a record of the reasons therefor. (h) In addition to all other penalties provided by this section, any person who willfully fails to make a return or to pay any tax imposed under the Kansas retailers' sales tax act, or who makes a false or fraudulent return, or fails to keep any books or records prescribed by this act, or who willfully violates any regulations of the secretary of revenue, for the enforcement and administration of this act, or who aids and abets another in attempting to evade the payment of any tax imposed by this act, or who violates any other provision of this act, shall, upon conviction thereof, be fined not less than $500, nor more than $10,000, or be imprisoned in the county jail not less than one month, nor more than six months, or be both so fined and imprisoned, in the discretion of the court. (i) No penalty assessed hereunder shall be collected if the taxpayer has had the tax abated on appeal, and any penalty collected upon such tax shall be refunded. (j) A person applying to the department for a refund of any tax imposed under the Kansas retailers' sales tax act that was not previously collected by the retailer, or that the retailer has already refunded to such person, shall be subject to a penalty of 50% of the amount of any such tax sought to be refunded. No such penalty shall be imposed against such person if the retailer collected the tax but did not remit such tax to the department.</p>
            </content>
            <subsection eId="79_3615__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>If any taxpayer shall fail to pay the tax required under this act at the time required by or under the provisions of this act, there shall be added to the unpaid balance of the tax, interest at the rate per month prescribed by subsection</p>
              </content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_3615__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of K.S.A. 79-2968, and amendments thereto, from the date the tax was due until paid.</p>
              </content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_3615__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>For all taxable years ending prior to January 1, 2002, if any taxpayer due to negligence or intentional disregard fails to file a return or pay the tax due at the time required by or under the provisions of this act, there shall be added to the tax a penalty in an amount equal to 10% of the unpaid balance of tax due.</p>
              </content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_3615__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>For all taxable years ending prior to January 1, 2002, if any person fails to make a return, or to pay any tax, within six months from the date the return or tax was due, except in the case of an extension of time granted by the secretary of revenue or the secretary's designee, there shall be added to the tax due a penalty equal to 25% of the unpaid balance of such tax due. Notwithstanding the foregoing, in the event an assessment is issued following a field audit for any period for which a return was filed by the taxpayer and all of the tax was paid pursuant to such return, a penalty shall be imposed for the period included in the assessment in the amount of 10% of the unpaid balance of tax due shown in the notice of assessment. If after review of a return for any period included in the assessment, the secretary or secretary's designee determines that the underpayment of tax was due to the failure of the taxpayer to make a reasonable attempt to comply with the provisions of this act, such penalty shall be imposed for the period included in the assessment in the amount of 25% of the unpaid balance of tax due.</p>
              </content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_3615__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>For all taxable years ending after December 31, 2001, if any taxpayer fails to file a return or pay the tax if one is due, at the time required by or under the provisions of this act, there shall be added to the tax an additional amount equal to 1% of the unpaid balance of the tax due for each month or fraction thereof during which such failure continues, not exceeding 24% in the aggregate, plus interest at the rate prescribed by subsection</p>
              </content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_3615__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of K.S.A. 79-2968, and amendments thereto, from the date the tax was due until paid. Notwithstanding the foregoing, in the event an assessment is issued following a field audit for any period for which a return was filed by the taxpayer and all of the tax was paid pursuant to such return, a penalty shall be imposed for the period included in the assessment in an amount of 1% per month not exceeding 10% of the unpaid balance of tax due shown in the notice of assessment. If after review of a return for any period included in the assessment, the secretary or secretary's designee determines that the underpayment of tax was due to the failure of the taxpayer to make a reasonable attempt to comply with the provisions of this act, such penalty shall be imposed for the period included in the assessment in the amount of 25% of the unpaid balance of tax due.</p>
              </content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_3615__subsec_e">
              <num>(e)</num>
              <content>
                <p>If any taxpayer, with fraudulent intent, fails to pay any tax or make, render or sign any return, or to supply any information, within the time required by or under the provisions of this act, there shall be added to the tax a penalty in an amount equal to 50% of the unpaid balance of tax due.</p>
              </content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_3615__subsec_f">
              <num>(f)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Penalty or interest applied under the provisions of subsections</p>
              </content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_3615__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>and</p>
              </content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_3615__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>shall be in addition to the penalty added under any other provisions of this section, but the provisions of subsections</p>
              </content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_3615__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>and</p>
              </content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_3615__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>shall be mutually exclusive of each other.</p>
              </content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_3615__subsec_g">
              <num>(g)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Whenever the secretary or the secretary's designee determines that the failure of the taxpayer to comply with the provisions of subsections</p>
              </content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_3615__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>and</p>
              </content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_3615__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of this section was due to reasonable causes, the secretary or the secretary's designee may waive or reduce any of the penalties and may reduce the interest rate to the underpayment rate prescribed and determined for the applicable period under section 6621 of the federal internal revenue code as in effect on January 1, 1994, upon making a record of the reasons therefor.</p>
              </content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_3615__subsec_h">
              <num>(h)</num>
              <content>
                <p>In addition to all other penalties provided by this section, any person who willfully fails to make a return or to pay any tax imposed under the Kansas retailers' sales tax act, or who makes a false or fraudulent return, or fails to keep any books or records prescribed by this act, or who willfully violates any regulations of the secretary of revenue, for the enforcement and administration of this act, or who aids and abets another in attempting to evade the payment of any tax imposed by this act, or who violates any other provision of this act, shall, upon conviction thereof, be fined not less than $500, nor more than $10,000, or be imprisoned in the county jail not less than one month, nor more than six months, or be both so fined and imprisoned, in the discretion of the court.</p>
              </content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_3615__subsec_i">
              <num>(i)</num>
              <content>
                <p>No penalty assessed hereunder shall be collected if the taxpayer has had the tax abated on appeal, and any penalty collected upon such tax shall be refunded.</p>
              </content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_3615__subsec_j">
              <num>(j)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A person applying to the department for a refund of any tax imposed under the Kansas retailers' sales tax act that was not previously collected by the retailer, or that the retailer has already refunded to such person, shall be subject to a penalty of 50% of the amount of any such tax sought to be refunded. No such penalty shall be imposed against such person if the retailer collected the tax but did not remit such tax to the department.</p>
              </content>
            </subsection>
          </section>
        </article>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
