<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ks-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-3610"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-3610"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ks-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ks"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-3610/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-3610/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ks-legislature"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-3610/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-3610/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ks-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ks/legislature" showAs="Kansas Legislature"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_79">
        <num>Chapter 79</num>
        <heading>Taxation</heading>
        <article eId="chp_79__art_36">
          <num>Article 36</num>
          <heading>Kansas Retailers' Sales Tax</heading>
          <section eId="sec_79_3610">
            <num>79-3610</num>
            <heading>Examination of returns; final determinations; notice; informal conferences; jeopardy assessments</heading>
            <content>
              <p>79-3610. Examination of returns; final determinations; notice; informal conferences; jeopardy assessments. The director of taxation shall examine all returns filed under the provisions of this act, and shall issue final determinations of tax liability hereunder in the manner prescribed by K.S.A. 79-3226, and amendments thereto, relating to income taxes. Any determination may be made on the basis of a generally recognized valid and reliable sampling technique, whether or not the person being audited has complete records of transactions and whether or not such person consents. In any such case, the director shall notify the taxpayer in writing of the sampling technique to be utilized, including the design and population of such sample. If the taxpayer demonstrates that any such technique used was not in accordance with generally recognized sampling techniques, the audit shall be dismissed with respect to that portion of the audit based upon such technique, and a new audit shall be performed. Within 60 days after the mailing of notice of the director's determination any taxpayer may request an informal conference with the secretary of revenue or the secretary's designee relating to such taxpayer's tax liability, including the issue of whether the use of a generally recognized sampling technique achieved a result that was reflective of the taxpayer's actual tax liability, and an informal conference thereon shall be conducted and the secretary of revenue or the secretary's designee shall make a final determination and give the taxpayer notice thereof. In case any person required by the provisions of this act to make a return fails or refuses to do so, the secretary of revenue or the secretary's designee, after notice to such person, shall make a final determination of the amount of such tax according to the best judgment and information of the secretary of revenue or the secretary's designee. Whenever the director of taxation has reason to believe that a person liable for tax under any provisions of the Kansas retailers' sales tax act is about to depart from the state or to remove such person's property therefrom, or to conceal oneself or such person's property therein, or to do any other act tending to prejudice, jeopardize or render wholly or partly ineffectual the collection of such sales tax unless proceedings be brought without delay, the director shall immediately make an assessment for all sales taxes due from such taxpayer, noting such finding on the assessment. The assessment shall be made on the basis of emergency proceedings in accordance with the provisions of K.S.A. 77-536 and amendments thereto. Thereupon a warrant shall forthwith be issued for the collection of the tax as provided in K.S.A. 79-3235, and amendments thereto. The taxpayer may within 15 days from the date of filing of such warrant request an informal conference with the secretary or the secretary's designee on the correctness of the jeopardy assessment.</p>
            </content>
          </section>
        </article>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
