<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ks-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-1439"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-1439"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ks-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ks"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-1439/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-1439/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ks-legislature"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-1439/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-1439/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ks-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ks/legislature" showAs="Kansas Legislature"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_79">
        <num>Chapter 79</num>
        <heading>Taxation</heading>
        <article eId="chp_79__art_14">
          <num>Article 14</num>
          <heading>Property Valuation, Equalizing Assessments, Appraisers and Assessment of Property</heading>
          <section eId="sec_79_1439">
            <num>79-1439</num>
            <heading>Appraisal of real and tangible personal property at fair market value in money; exceptions; rate of assessment</heading>
            <content>
              <p>79-1439. Appraisal of real and tangible personal property at fair market value in money; exceptions; rate of assessment. (a) All real and tangible personal property which is subject to general ad valorem taxation shall be appraised uniformly and equally as to class and, unless otherwise specified herein, shall be appraised at its fair market value, as defined in K.S.A. 79-503a, and amendments thereto. (b) Property shall be classified into the following classes and assessed at the percentage of value prescribed therefor: (1) Real property shall be assessed as to subclass at the following percentages of value: (A) Real property used for residential purposes including multi-family residential real property, real property necessary to accommodate a residential community of mobile or manufactured homes including the real property upon which such homes are located, residential real property used partially for day care home purposes if such home has been registered or licensed pursuant to K.S.A. 65-501 et seq., and amendments thereto, and real property used for bed and breakfast purposes at 11.5%. As used in this paragraph &quot;bed and breakfast&quot; means a property with five or fewer bedrooms available for overnight guests who stay for not more than 28 consecutive days for which there is compliance with all zoning or other applicable ordinances or laws which pertain to facilities which lodge and feed guests; (B) land devoted to agricultural use valued pursuant to K.S.A. 79-1476, and amendments thereto, at 30%; (C) vacant lots at 12%; (D) real property which is owned and operated by a not-for-profit organization not subject to federal income taxation pursuant to section 501 of the federal internal revenue code and included herein pursuant to K.S.A. 79-1439a, and amendments thereto, at 12%; (E) public utility real property, except railroad property which shall be assessed at the average rate all other commercial and industrial property is assessed, at 33%. As used in this paragraph, &quot;public utility&quot; shall have the meaning ascribed thereto by K.S.A. 79-5a01, and amendments thereto; (F) real property used for commercial and industrial purposes and buildings and other improvements located upon land devoted to agricultural use at 25%; and (G) all other urban and rural real property not otherwise specifically subclassed at 30%. (2) Personal property shall be classified into the following classes and assessed at the percentage of value prescribed therefor: (A) Mobile homes used for residential purposes at 11.5%; (B) mineral leasehold interests, except oil leasehold interests the average daily production from which is five barrels or less, and natural gas leasehold interests, the average daily production from which is 100 mcf or less, which shall be assessed at 25%, at 30%; (C) public utility tangible personal property including inventories thereof, except railroad personal property including inventories thereof, which shall be assessed at the average rate all other commercial and industrial property is assessed, at 33%. As used in this paragraph, &quot;public utility&quot; shall have the meaning ascribed thereto by K.S.A. 79-5a01, and amendments thereto; (D) all categories of motor vehicles listed and taxed pursuant to K.S.A. 79-306d, and amendments thereto, and, prior to January 1, 2014, over-the-road motor vehicles defined pursuant to K.S.A. 79-6a01, and amendments thereto, at 30%; (E) commercial and industrial machinery and equipment, including rolling equipment defined pursuant to K.S.A. 79-6a01, and amendments thereto, which, if its economic life is seven years or more, shall be valued at its retail cost when new less seven-year straight-line depreciation, or which, if its economic life is less than seven years, shall be valued at its retail cost when new less straight-line depreciation over its economic life, except that, the value so obtained for such property as long as it is being used shall not be less than 20% of the retail cost when new of such property at 25%; and (F) all other tangible personal property not otherwise specifically classified at 30%.</p>
            </content>
            <subsection eId="79_1439__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>All real and tangible personal property which is subject to general ad valorem taxation shall be appraised uniformly and equally as to class and, unless otherwise specified herein, shall be appraised at its fair market value, as defined in K.S.A. 79-503a, and amendments thereto.</p>
              </content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_1439__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Property shall be classified into the following classes and assessed at the percentage of value prescribed therefor:</p>
              </content>
              <paragraph eId="79_1439__subsec_b__para_1">
                <num>(1)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Real property shall be assessed as to subclass at the following percentages of value: (A) Real property used for residential purposes including multi-family residential real property, real property necessary to accommodate a residential community of mobile or manufactured homes including the real property upon which such homes are located, residential real property used partially for day care home purposes if such home has been registered or licensed pursuant to K.S.A. 65-501 et seq., and amendments thereto, and real property used for bed and breakfast purposes at 11.5%. As used in this paragraph &quot;bed and breakfast&quot; means a property with five or fewer bedrooms available for overnight guests who stay for not more than 28 consecutive days for which there is compliance with all zoning or other applicable ordinances or laws which pertain to facilities which lodge and feed guests; (B) land devoted to agricultural use valued pursuant to K.S.A. 79-1476, and amendments thereto, at 30%; (C) vacant lots at 12%; (D) real property which is owned and operated by a not-for-profit organization not subject to federal income taxation pursuant to section 501 of the federal internal revenue code and included herein pursuant to K.S.A. 79-1439a, and amendments thereto, at 12%; (E) public utility real property, except railroad property which shall be assessed at the average rate all other commercial and industrial property is assessed, at 33%. As used in this paragraph, &quot;public utility&quot; shall have the meaning ascribed thereto by K.S.A. 79-5a01, and amendments thereto; (F) real property used for commercial and industrial purposes and buildings and other improvements located upon land devoted to agricultural use at 25%; and (G) all other urban and rural real property not otherwise specifically subclassed at 30%.</p>
                </content>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph eId="79_1439__subsec_b__para_2">
                <num>(2)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Personal property shall be classified into the following classes and assessed at the percentage of value prescribed therefor: (A) Mobile homes used for residential purposes at 11.5%; (B) mineral leasehold interests, except oil leasehold interests the average daily production from which is five barrels or less, and natural gas leasehold interests, the average daily production from which is 100 mcf or less, which shall be assessed at 25%, at 30%; (C) public utility tangible personal property including inventories thereof, except railroad personal property including inventories thereof, which shall be assessed at the average rate all other commercial and industrial property is assessed, at 33%. As used in this paragraph, &quot;public utility&quot; shall have the meaning ascribed thereto by K.S.A. 79-5a01, and amendments thereto; (D) all categories of motor vehicles listed and taxed pursuant to K.S.A. 79-306d, and amendments thereto, and, prior to January 1, 2014, over-the-road motor vehicles defined pursuant to K.S.A. 79-6a01, and amendments thereto, at 30%; (E) commercial and industrial machinery and equipment, including rolling equipment defined pursuant to K.S.A. 79-6a01, and amendments thereto, which, if its economic life is seven years or more, shall be valued at its retail cost when new less seven-year straight-line depreciation, or which, if its economic life is less than seven years, shall be valued at its retail cost when new less straight-line depreciation over its economic life, except that, the value so obtained for such property as long as it is being used shall not be less than 20% of the retail cost when new of such property at 25%; and (F) all other tangible personal property not otherwise specifically classified at 30%.</p>
                </content>
              </paragraph>
            </subsection>
          </section>
        </article>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
