<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ks-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-345"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-345"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ks-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ks"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-345/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-345/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ks-legislature"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-345/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-345/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ks-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ks/legislature" showAs="Kansas Legislature"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_79">
        <num>Chapter 79</num>
        <heading>Taxation</heading>
        <article eId="chp_79__art_3">
          <num>Article 3</num>
          <heading>Listing Property for Taxation</heading>
          <section eId="sec_79_345">
            <num>79-345</num>
            <heading>Section 79-345</heading>
            <content>
              <p>2023-2024
Legislative Sessions
Return to current session
Home •
News •
Contact •
House
Leadership
Committees
Rules
Current Events
Seating Chart
Roster
Chief Clerk of the House
Senate
Leadership
Committees
Confirmations
Rules
Current Events
Seating Chart
Roster
Secretary of the Senate
Legislators
House Leadership
House Roster
Senate Leadership
Senate Roster
Committees
Committees
Standing
Joint
Special and Select
Commission
Subcommittee
Task Force
Other
Conference Schedules
Conference Committees
Committee Bill Hearings
Bills &amp; Laws
Senate Bills
House Bills
Statute
Reports
Actions and Subject Index Report
How a bill becomes law (pdf)
Kansas Constitution
Contact the Revisor
Journals
House Journal
Senate Journal
What is a Journal?
Calendars
House Calendar
Senate Calendar
What Is A Calendar?
Research
Memos/Reports/Publications
Appropriations
Revenue/Taxation
Redistricting
About KLRD
Historical
2025-26 Regular Sessions
2024 Special Session
2021-2022 Regular Sessions
2021 Special Session
2020 Special Session
2019-2020 Regular Sessions
2017-2018 Regular Sessions
2016 Special Session
2015-2016 Regular Sessions
2013-2014 Regular Sessions
2013 Special Session
2011-2012 Regular Sessions
1997 - 2010 Sessions
2000 - 2010 Committee Data
Find Bill
Bill/Resolution Lookup:
Find Your Legislator
Chamber:
Both Chambers
Senate
House
Party:
All Parties
Republican
Democrat
Search by Your Address
Legislative Deadlines
Senate Deadlines
(PDF)
House Deadlines
(PDF)
Current Events
Statute
Legislative Resources
Administrative Services
Division of Post Audit
Information Services
Research Department
Revisor of Statutes
LCC Policies
About the Legislature
Other State Resources
Kansas.gov
Ethics Commission
How Do I…
Become A Legislative Intern
Become A Legislative Page
Apply For Session Work
Dec. 31, 2025
-A
+A
House Status:
Adjourned until Monday, January 13, 2025 at 02:00 p.m.
Senate Status:
Adjourned until Monday, January 13, 2025 at 02:00 p.m.
you are here:
Home
»
Statute
»
Chapter 79
»
Article 34
»
Section 5
»
2024
 Statute
Prev
Article 34. - MOTOR VEHICLE FUEL TAXES
Next
79-3405.
Additional bond; financial statements; revocation of license; release of sureties; renewal of license; interstate commerce exempt.
The director may at any time require any distributor, manufacturer, importer or exporter to furnish such additional bond with authorized corporate surety, as shall be necessary to secure at all times the payment by such person to the state of all taxes, penalties and interest due under the provisions of this act. If any distributor, manufacturer, importer or exporter shall fail to file such additional bond within 10 days after receipt of written notice mailed or otherwise delivered to such person by the director, the director may suspend or revoke the license or licenses issued to such person, and collect all taxes, penalties and interest accrued against such distributor, manufacturer, importer or exporter. For the purpose of determining whether an existing bond or bonds are sufficient, the director may at any time, by mailed written notice, or otherwise delivered, require any distributor, manufacturer, importer or exporter to furnish a financial statement in such form as the director may prescribe. Upon failure of any distributor, manufacturer, importer or exporter to furnish a sworn financial statement within 20 days after receipt of such written notice, the director may suspend or revoke any or all licenses issued to such person, and shall collect all taxes, penalties, and interest accrued against such distributor, manufacturer, importer or exporter.
Any surety on a bond furnished by a distributor, manufacturer, importer or exporter as provided shall be released and discharged from any and all liability to the state accruing on such bond after the expiration of 60 days from the date upon which such surety shall have lodged with the director a written request to be released and discharged, but this provision shall not operate to relieve, release, or discharge the surety from any liability already accrued or which shall accrue before the expiration of the sixty-day period. The director shall promptly, upon receiving any such request, notify the distributor, manufacturer, importer or exporter who furnished the bond and unless the distributor, manufacturer, importer or exporter shall, on or before the expiration of such sixty-day period, file with the director a new bond fully complying with the provisions of this act, the director shall revoke and cancel such distributor's, manufacturer's, importer's or exporter's license or licenses and notify the distributor, manufacturer, importer or exporter by registered mail or otherwise.
Licenses issued under the provisions of this act may be renewed annually before the first day of November upon an application to the director, but no licenses shall be renewed until the applicant shall file with the director a bond in such amounts as shall be fixed by the director and fully complying with the provisions of this act. Nothing contained in this act shall require the filing of an application or bond, or the possession or display of a motor-vehicle-fuels or special fuels license, for the use, sale and delivery of motor-vehicle fuels or special fuels exclusively in interstate or foreign commerce not within the taxing power of the state, or for use by, or sale or delivery to, the United States government.
History:
L. 1933, ch. 317, § 5; L. 1939, ch. 330, § 3; L. 1992, ch. 106, § 7; L. 1995, ch. 262, § 27; July 1.
Prev
Article 34. - MOTOR VEHICLE FUEL TAXES
Next
2025. Powered by KLISS. Rendered: 2025-12-31T10:14:22. Head Rev No: 1485844(I)</p>
            </content>
          </section>
        </article>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
