<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ks-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-5212"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-5212"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ks-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ks"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-5212/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-5212/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ks-legislature"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-5212/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-5212/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ks-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ks/legislature" showAs="Kansas Legislature"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_79">
        <num>Chapter 79</num>
        <heading>Taxation</heading>
        <article eId="chp_79__art_52">
          <num>Article 52</num>
          <heading>Food Sales Tax Credit</heading>
          <section eId="sec_79_5212">
            <num>79-5212</num>
            <heading>Taxation of marijuana and controlled substances; warrants for collection of tax, issuance, execution and returns; seizure and sale of property; tax liens; disposition of firearms</heading>
            <content>
              <p>79-5212. Taxation of marijuana and controlled substances; warrants for collection of tax, issuance, execution and returns; seizure and sale of property; tax liens; disposition of firearms. (a) Whenever a taxpayer liable to pay any tax, penalty or interest assessed pursuant to K.S.A. 79-5205, and amendments thereto, refuses or neglects to immediately pay the amount due, the director of taxation may issue one or more warrants for the immediate collection of the amount due, directed to the sheriff of any county of the state commanding the sheriff to seize and sell the real and personal property of the taxpayer, or to seize, appraise and dispose of the firearms of the taxpayer, found within the sheriff's county to satisfy the amount specified on the warrant and the cost of executing the warrant. The director of taxation may also issue one or more warrants directed to any employee of the department of revenue commanding the employee to seize and sell the real and personal property of the taxpayer, or to seize, appraise and dispose of the firearms of the taxpayer, found anywhere within the state of Kansas to satisfy the amount specified on the warrant and the cost of executing the warrant. A copy of the warrant shall also be mailed to the taxpayer at the taxpayer's last known address or served upon the taxpayer in person. (b) The sheriff or department of revenue employee shall proceed to execute upon the warrant in the same manner as provided for attachment orders by K.S.A. 60-706, 60-707 and 60-710, and amendments thereto, except as otherwise provided herein. In the execution of a warrant issued to a department of revenue employee, the employee shall have all of the powers conferred by law upon sheriffs. Any law enforcement officer may assist in the execution of a warrant if requested to do so by a department of revenue employee. (c) No law exempting any goods and chattels, land and tenements from forced sale under execution shall apply to a seizure and sale, or in the case of firearms, sale or disposal, under any warrant. (d) A third party holding funds or other personal property of the taxpayer shall immediately, or as soon thereafter as possible, after service of the warrant on such third party, deliver such funds or other personal property to the sheriff or department of revenue employee, who shall then deliver such to the director of taxation or the director's designee for deposit toward the balance due on the taxpayer's assessment. (e) The sheriff or department of revenue employee shall make return of such warrant to the director of taxation within 60 days from the date of the warrant. If property is seized, then the sheriff or department of revenue employee shall also make return of such warrant to the clerk of the district court in the county where the property was seized. (f) (1) If the taxpayer fails to appeal the assessment as provided by K.S.A. 79-5205(b), and amendments thereto, or if the taxpayer requests a hearing and a final order has been entered by the director of taxation as to the correctness of the assessment, then the sheriff or department of revenue employee shall sell the seized property at public auction, except that firearms may be sold at public auction or disposed of as provided in paragraph (2). The provisions of K.S.A. 60-2406, and amendments thereto, shall apply to liens against the property being sold. Notice of the sale of personal property shall be given in accordance with K.S.A. 60-2409, and amendments thereto. Notice of the sale of real property shall be given in accordance with K.S.A. 60-2410, and amendments thereto. The taxpayer shall have the right to redeem real property within a period of six months from the date of the sale. (2) In the case of seized firearms not sold, the director of taxation shall obtain an appraisal value performed by a federally licensed firearms dealer or an employee thereof. Such value shall be credited against the taxpayer's outstanding liability. Subsequent to such appraisal and credit against the taxpayer's outstanding liability, the director shall transfer such firearm or firearms as follows: (A) If the firearm or firearms have historical significance, the director may transfer the firearm or firearms to the Kansas state historical society; (B) the director may transfer the firearm or firearms to the secretary of wildlife and parks; (C) the director may transfer the firearm or firearms to the director of the Kansas bureau of investigation; or (D) the director may transfer the firearm or firearms to such city or county law enforcement agency where the firearm was seized. (3) At least 30 days prior to the transfer of such firearm or firearms, pursuant to this subsection, the director shall give written notice by mail to the taxpayer at the taxpayer's last known address of the appraised value of such firearm or firearms and the date that the director intends to transfer such firearm or firearms. The taxpayer may appeal the appraised value of any such firearm or firearms by filing a written request for a hearing before the district court in which the tax warrant used to seize such firearm or firearms was filed. Such request must be filed with the district court within 15 days after such notice to the taxpayer was mailed by the director. If no appeal is filed with the district court within 15 days, or if upon appeal the district court rules against the taxpayer, the director shall transfer such firearm or firearms. (g) The director of taxation may also direct the sheriff or department of revenue employee to file any warrant issued pursuant to subsection (a) with the clerk of the district court of any county in Kansas, and thereupon the clerk shall enter in the appearance docket the name of the taxpayer mentioned in the warrant, the amount of the tax or portion of it, interest and penalties for which the warrant is issued and the date such copy is filed and note the taxpayer's name in the general index. No fee shall be charged for such entry. The amount of such warrant shall thereupon become a lien upon the title to, and interest in, the real property of the taxpayer located within such county. Thereupon, the director of taxation shall have the same remedies to collect the amount of the tax, penalty and interest, as if the state of Kansas had recovered judgment against the taxpayer, including immediately garnishing the wages or other property of the taxpayer pursuant to K.S.A. 60-716 et seq., and amendments thereto. Such remedies shall be in addition to the other collection remedies provided herein. (h) The director of taxation shall have the right at any time to issue alias warrants until the full amount of the tax, penalty and interest is collected.</p>
            </content>
            <subsection eId="79_5212__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Whenever a taxpayer liable to pay any tax, penalty or interest assessed pursuant to K.S.A. 79-5205, and amendments thereto, refuses or neglects to immediately pay the amount due, the director of taxation may issue one or more warrants for the immediate collection of the amount due, directed to the sheriff of any county of the state commanding the sheriff to seize and sell the real and personal property of the taxpayer, or to seize, appraise and dispose of the firearms of the taxpayer, found within the sheriff's county to satisfy the amount specified on the warrant and the cost of executing the warrant. The director of taxation may also issue one or more warrants directed to any employee of the department of revenue commanding the employee to seize and sell the real and personal property of the taxpayer, or to seize, appraise and dispose of the firearms of the taxpayer, found anywhere within the state of Kansas to satisfy the amount specified on the warrant and the cost of executing the warrant. A copy of the warrant shall also be mailed to the taxpayer at the taxpayer's last known address or served upon the taxpayer in person.</p>
              </content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_5212__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The sheriff or department of revenue employee shall proceed to execute upon the warrant in the same manner as provided for attachment orders by K.S.A. 60-706, 60-707 and 60-710, and amendments thereto, except as otherwise provided herein. In the execution of a warrant issued to a department of revenue employee, the employee shall have all of the powers conferred by law upon sheriffs. Any law enforcement officer may assist in the execution of a warrant if requested to do so by a department of revenue employee.</p>
              </content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_5212__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>No law exempting any goods and chattels, land and tenements from forced sale under execution shall apply to a seizure and sale, or in the case of firearms, sale or disposal, under any warrant.</p>
              </content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_5212__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A third party holding funds or other personal property of the taxpayer shall immediately, or as soon thereafter as possible, after service of the warrant on such third party, deliver such funds or other personal property to the sheriff or department of revenue employee, who shall then deliver such to the director of taxation or the director's designee for deposit toward the balance due on the taxpayer's assessment.</p>
              </content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_5212__subsec_e">
              <num>(e)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The sheriff or department of revenue employee shall make return of such warrant to the director of taxation within 60 days from the date of the warrant. If property is seized, then the sheriff or department of revenue employee shall also make return of such warrant to the clerk of the district court in the county where the property was seized.</p>
              </content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_5212__subsec_f">
              <num>(f)</num>
              <paragraph eId="79_5212__subsec_f__para_1">
                <num>(1)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>If the taxpayer fails to appeal the assessment as provided by K.S.A. 79-5205</p>
                </content>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph eId="79_5212__subsec_f__para_2">
                <num>(2)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>In the case of seized firearms not sold, the director of taxation shall obtain an appraisal value performed by a federally licensed firearms dealer or an employee thereof. Such value shall be credited against the taxpayer's outstanding liability. Subsequent to such appraisal and credit against the taxpayer's outstanding liability, the director shall transfer such firearm or firearms as follows: (A) If the firearm or firearms have historical significance, the director may transfer the firearm or firearms to the Kansas state historical society; (B) the director may transfer the firearm or firearms to the secretary of wildlife and parks; (C) the director may transfer the firearm or firearms to the director of the Kansas bureau of investigation; or (D) the director may transfer the firearm or firearms to such city or county law enforcement agency where the firearm was seized.</p>
                </content>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph eId="79_5212__subsec_f__para_3">
                <num>(3)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>At least 30 days prior to the transfer of such firearm or firearms, pursuant to this subsection, the director shall give written notice by mail to the taxpayer at the taxpayer's last known address of the appraised value of such firearm or firearms and the date that the director intends to transfer such firearm or firearms. The taxpayer may appeal the appraised value of any such firearm or firearms by filing a written request for a hearing before the district court in which the tax warrant used to seize such firearm or firearms was filed. Such request must be filed with the district court within 15 days after such notice to the taxpayer was mailed by the director. If no appeal is filed with the district court within 15 days, or if upon appeal the district court rules against the taxpayer, the director shall transfer such firearm or firearms.</p>
                </content>
              </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_5212__subsec_g">
              <num>(g)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The director of taxation may also direct the sheriff or department of revenue employee to file any warrant issued pursuant to subsection</p>
              </content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_5212__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>with the clerk of the district court of any county in Kansas, and thereupon the clerk shall enter in the appearance docket the name of the taxpayer mentioned in the warrant, the amount of the tax or portion of it, interest and penalties for which the warrant is issued and the date such copy is filed and note the taxpayer's name in the general index. No fee shall be charged for such entry. The amount of such warrant shall thereupon become a lien upon the title to, and interest in, the real property of the taxpayer located within such county. Thereupon, the director of taxation shall have the same remedies to collect the amount of the tax, penalty and interest, as if the state of Kansas had recovered judgment against the taxpayer, including immediately garnishing the wages or other property of the taxpayer pursuant to K.S.A. 60-716 et seq., and amendments thereto. Such remedies shall be in addition to the other collection remedies provided herein.</p>
              </content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_5212__subsec_h">
              <num>(h)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The director of taxation shall have the right at any time to issue alias warrants until the full amount of the tax, penalty and interest is collected.</p>
              </content>
            </subsection>
          </section>
        </article>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
