<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ks-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-3374"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-3374"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ks-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ks"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-3374/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-3374/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ks-legislature"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-3374/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-3374/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ks-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ks/legislature" showAs="Kansas Legislature"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_79">
        <num>Chapter 79</num>
        <heading>Taxation</heading>
        <article eId="chp_79__art_33">
          <num>Article 33</num>
          <heading>Cigarettes and Tobacco Products</heading>
          <section eId="sec_79_3374">
            <num>79-3374</num>
            <heading>License fees; surety bond; application for each place of business</heading>
            <content>
              <p>79-3374. License fees; surety bond; application for each place of business. Each application for a distributor's license shall be accompanied by a fee of twenty-five dollars ($25). The application shall also be accompanied by a corporate surety bond issued by a surety company authorized to do business in this state, conditioned for the payment when due of all taxes, penalties and accrued interest which may be due the state. The bond shall be in an amount to be determined by the director and in a form prescribed by the director. Whenever it is the opinion of the director that the bond given by a licensee is inadequate in amount to fully protect the state, he or she shall require an additional bond in such amount as he or she deems sufficient. A separate application for a license shall be made for each place of business at which a distributor proposes to engage in business as such under this act, but an applicant may provide one bond in an amount determined by the director for all applications made by him or her. A distributor applying for a license between June thirtieth and December thirty-first of any year shall be required to pay only one-half of the license fee provided for herein.</p>
            </content>
          </section>
        </article>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
