<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ks-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-1119"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-1119"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ks-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ks"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-1119/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-1119/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ks-legislature"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-1119/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-1119/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ks-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ks/legislature" showAs="Kansas Legislature"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_79">
        <num>Chapter 79</num>
        <heading>Taxation</heading>
        <article eId="chp_79__art_11">
          <num>Article 11</num>
          <heading>Banks, Banking Businesses, Trust Companies and Savings and Loan Associations</heading>
          <section eId="sec_79_1119">
            <num>79-1119</num>
            <heading>Reports, statements, lists and returns; preservation; confidentiality, exceptions; performance of certain activities by administrative personnel unlawful; penalties for violations</heading>
            <content>
              <p>79-1119. Reports, statements, lists and returns; preservation; confidentiality, exceptions; performance of certain activities by administrative personnel unlawful; penalties for violations. (a) All reports, statements, lists and returns required under the provisions of article 11 of chapter 79 of the Kansas Statutes Annotated, and amendments thereto, shall be preserved for three years and thereafter until the director of taxation orders them to be destroyed. (b) Except in accordance with proper judicial order, or as provided in subsection (c) or K.S.A. 46-1106, and amendments thereto, it shall be unlawful for the director of taxation, or any deputy, agent, clerk or other officer, employee or former employee of the department of revenue or any other state officer or employee or former state officer or employee to divulge, or to make known in any way, the amount of income or any particulars set forth or disclosed in any report, statement, list, return, federal return or federal return information required under the provisions of article 11 of chapter 79 of the Kansas Statutes Annotated, and amendments thereto; and it shall be unlawful for the director of taxation, or any deputy, agent, clerk or other officer or employee of the department of revenue engaged in the administration of the tax imposed under the provisions of article 11 of chapter 79 of the Kansas Statutes Annotated, and amendments thereto, to engage in the business or profession of tax accounting or to accept employment, with or without consideration, for any person, firm or corporation for the purpose, directly or indirectly, or preparing tax returns or reports required by the laws of the state of Kansas, by any other state or by the United States government, or to accept any employment for the purpose of advising, preparing material or data, or the auditing of books or records to be used in an effort to defeat or cancel any tax or part thereof that has been assessed by the state of Kansas, any other state or by the United States government. (c) The secretary or the secretary's designee may: (1) Publish statistics, so classified as to prevent the identification of particular reports or returns and the items thereof; (2) allow the inspection of returns by the attorney general or other legal representatives of the state; (3) provide the post auditor access to all statements, lists, reports or returns in accordance with and subject to the provisions of K.S.A. 46-1106(g), and amendments thereto; or (4) disclose to the secretary of commerce specific taxpayer information related to financial information previously submitted by the taxpayer to the secretary of commerce concerning or relevant to any privilege tax credits, for purposes of verification of such information or evaluating the effectiveness of any tax credit program administered by the secretary of commerce. (d) Any person receiving information under the provisions of subsection (c) shall be subject to the confidentiality provisions of subsection (b) and to the penalty provisions of subsection (e). (e) Any violation of subsection (b) or (c) shall be a class A misdemeanor; and if the offender be an officer or employee of the state, such officer or employee shall be dismissed from office. (f) Notwithstanding the provisions of this section, the secretary of revenue may, in his or her discretion, permit the commissioner of internal revenue of the United States, or the proper official of any state imposing an income tax or privilege tax on financial institutions, or the authorized representative of either, to inspect the reports, statements, lists or returns made under the provisions of article 11 of chapter 79 of the Kansas Statutes Annotated, and amendments thereto, and the secretary of revenue may make available or furnish to the taxing officials of any other state or the commissioner of internal revenue of the United States or other taxing officials of the federal government, or their authorized representatives, information contained in statements, lists, reports, or returns or any audit thereof or the report of any investigation made with respect thereto, filed pursuant to any of the provisions of article 11 of chapter 79 of the Kansas Statutes Annotated, and amendments thereto, as the secretary may consider proper, but such information shall not be used for any other purpose than that of the administration of tax laws of such state or of the United States.</p>
            </content>
            <subsection eId="79_1119__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>All reports, statements, lists and returns required under the provisions of article 11 of chapter 79 of the Kansas Statutes Annotated, and amendments thereto, shall be preserved for three years and thereafter until the director of taxation orders them to be destroyed.</p>
              </content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_1119__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Except in accordance with proper judicial order, or as provided in subsection</p>
              </content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_1119__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>or K.S.A. 46-1106, and amendments thereto, it shall be unlawful for the director of taxation, or any deputy, agent, clerk or other officer, employee or former employee of the department of revenue or any other state officer or employee or former state officer or employee to divulge, or to make known in any way, the amount of income or any particulars set forth or disclosed in any report, statement, list, return, federal return or federal return information required under the provisions of article 11 of chapter 79 of the Kansas Statutes Annotated, and amendments thereto; and it shall be unlawful for the director of taxation, or any deputy, agent, clerk or other officer or employee of the department of revenue engaged in the administration of the tax imposed under the provisions of article 11 of chapter 79 of the Kansas Statutes Annotated, and amendments thereto, to engage in the business or profession of tax accounting or to accept employment, with or without consideration, for any person, firm or corporation for the purpose, directly or indirectly, or preparing tax returns or reports required by the laws of the state of Kansas, by any other state or by the United States government, or to accept any employment for the purpose of advising, preparing material or data, or the auditing of books or records to be used in an effort to defeat or cancel any tax or part thereof that has been assessed by the state of Kansas, any other state or by the United States government.</p>
              </content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_1119__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The secretary or the secretary's designee may:</p>
              </content>
              <paragraph eId="79_1119__subsec_c__para_1">
                <num>(1)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Publish statistics, so classified as to prevent the identification of particular reports or returns and the items thereof;</p>
                </content>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph eId="79_1119__subsec_c__para_2">
                <num>(2)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>allow the inspection of returns by the attorney general or other legal representatives of the state;</p>
                </content>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph eId="79_1119__subsec_c__para_3">
                <num>(3)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>provide the post auditor access to all statements, lists, reports or returns in accordance with and subject to the provisions of K.S.A. 46-1106</p>
                </content>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph eId="79_1119__subsec_c__para_4">
                <num>(4)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>disclose to the secretary of commerce specific taxpayer information related to financial information previously submitted by the taxpayer to the secretary of commerce concerning or relevant to any privilege tax credits, for purposes of verification of such information or evaluating the effectiveness of any tax credit program administered by the secretary of commerce.</p>
                </content>
              </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_1119__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Any person receiving information under the provisions of subsection</p>
              </content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_1119__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>shall be subject to the confidentiality provisions of subsection</p>
              </content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_1119__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>and to the penalty provisions of subsection</p>
              </content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_1119__subsec_e">
              <num>(e)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Any violation of subsection</p>
              </content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_1119__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>or</p>
              </content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_1119__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>shall be a class A misdemeanor; and if the offender be an officer or employee of the state, such officer or employee shall be dismissed from office.</p>
              </content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_1119__subsec_f">
              <num>(f)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Notwithstanding the provisions of this section, the secretary of revenue may, in his or her discretion, permit the commissioner of internal revenue of the United States, or the proper official of any state imposing an income tax or privilege tax on financial institutions, or the authorized representative of either, to inspect the reports, statements, lists or returns made under the provisions of article 11 of chapter 79 of the Kansas Statutes Annotated, and amendments thereto, and the secretary of revenue may make available or furnish to the taxing officials of any other state or the commissioner of internal revenue of the United States or other taxing officials of the federal government, or their authorized representatives, information contained in statements, lists, reports, or returns or any audit thereof or the report of any investigation made with respect thereto, filed pursuant to any of the provisions of article 11 of chapter 79 of the Kansas Statutes Annotated, and amendments thereto, as the secretary may consider proper, but such information shall not be used for any other purpose than that of the administration of tax laws of such state or of the United States.</p>
              </content>
            </subsection>
          </section>
        </article>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
