<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ks-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-3425"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-3425"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ks-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ks"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-3425/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-3425/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ks-legislature"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-3425/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-3425/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ks-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ks/legislature" showAs="Kansas Legislature"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_79">
        <num>Chapter 79</num>
        <heading>Taxation</heading>
        <article eId="chp_79__art_34">
          <num>Article 34</num>
          <heading>Motor Vehicle Fuel Taxes</heading>
          <section eId="sec_79_3425">
            <num>79-3425</num>
            <heading>Payment into state treasury; distribution of proceeds of tax</heading>
            <content>
              <p>79-3425. Payment into state treasury; distribution of proceeds of tax. All of the amounts collected under the motor-fuel tax law and amendments thereto, except amounts collected pursuant to K.S.A. 79-3408c, and amendments thereto, shall be remitted by the director to the state treasurer in accordance with the provisions of K.S.A. 75-4215, and amendments thereto. Upon receipt of each such remittance, the state treasurer shall deposit the entire amount in the state treasury. The state treasurer shall credit such amount as the director shall order in the motor-vehicle fuel tax refund fund to be used for the purpose of paying motor-vehicle fuel tax refunds as provided by law. The state treasurer shall credit the remainder of such amounts as follows: To the state highway fund amounts specified in K.S.A. 79-34,142, and amendments thereto, to a special city and county highway fund which is hereby created, amounts specified in K.S.A. 79-34,142, and amendments thereto, to be apportioned and distributed in the manner provided in K.S.A. 79-3425c, and amendments thereto, and to the current production account and the new production account of the Kansas qualified agricultural ethyl alcohol producer incentive fund, which is hereby created in the state treasury, in the amount and in the manner specified in K.S.A. 79-34,161, and amendments thereto, to be expended in the manner provided in K.S.A. 79-34,162, and amendments thereto.</p>
            </content>
          </section>
        </article>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
