<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ks-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-3495"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-3495"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ks-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ks"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-3495/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-3495/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ks-legislature"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-3495/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-3495/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ks-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ks/legislature" showAs="Kansas Legislature"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_79">
        <num>Chapter 79</num>
        <heading>Taxation</heading>
        <article eId="chp_79__art_34">
          <num>Article 34</num>
          <heading>Motor Vehicle Fuel Taxes</heading>
          <section eId="sec_79_3495">
            <num>79-3495</num>
            <heading>User and dealer reports, monthly or annual; payment of tax, monthly or annual; interest and penalties; LP-gas user and dealer licenses; application; refusal of license; filing fee</heading>
            <content>
              <p>79-3495. User and dealer reports, monthly or annual; payment of tax, monthly or annual; interest and penalties; LP-gas user and dealer licenses; application; refusal of license; filing fee. (a) Each LP-gas user or LP-gas dealer subject to the provisions of this act must, on or before the 25 th day of each calendar month, file with the director a report, certified to be true and correct, on a form prescribed and furnished by the director, showing the total number of gallons of LP-gas placed into fuel supply tank or tanks of any motor vehicle while such vehicle is within this state during the preceding calendar month, including the number of gallons on hand at the beginning and end of each month, the number of gallons received from any and all sources supported by detailed schedules of receipts, purchases and withdrawals for sale or use, and such other information as the director may require. Each LP-gas user or LP-gas dealer at the time of filing each monthly report must pay to the director the full amount of tax due for the preceding calendar month at the rate provided for in this act. (b) Any tax imposed under the provisions of this act not paid on or before the 25 th of the month succeeding the calendar month in which the LP-gas was used shall be deemed delinquent and shall bear interest at the rate per month, or fraction thereof prescribed by subsection (a) of K.S.A. 79-2968, and amendments thereto, from such due date until paid, and in addition thereto there is hereby imposed upon all amounts of such tax remaining due and unpaid after such due date a penalty in the amount of 5% thereof, and such penalty shall be by the director added to and collected as a part of such tax. If the LP-gas user or LP-gas dealer furnishes evidence to the director that the delinquency was due to causes beyond such user's or dealer's reasonable control, and if in the opinion of the director the delinquency was not the result of willful negligence of the LP-gas user or LP-gas dealer the penalty or interest or both may be waived or reduced by the director. (c) The director, if satisfied that the enforcement of the act is not adversely affected, may exempt any LP-gas user or LP-gas dealer from the monthly reporting and payment requirements of this act and require in lieu thereof annual payment of the tax due hereunder and annual reporting on forms provided by the director. (d) Whenever the secretary or the secretary's designee determines that the failure of the taxpayer to comply with the provisions of subsection (b) was due to reasonable causes, the secretary or the secretary's designee may waive or reduce any of the penalties and may reduce the interest rate to the underpayment rate prescribed and determined for the applicable period under section 6621 of the federal internal revenue code as in effect on January 1, 1994, upon making a record of the reasons therefor. (e) It shall be unlawful for any LP-gas user or LP-gas dealer to use or sell any LP-gas within this state unless such LP-gas user or LP-gas dealer is a holder of an uncanceled, unsuspended or unrevoked license issued by the director, unless such user has remitted the tax to a licensed LP-gas dealer. To procure such license every applicant shall file with the director an application upon oath and in such form as the director may prescribe, setting forth the name and addresses, the kind of business, and the designation of the exact locations or places of business where LP-gas is delivered or placed into the fuel supply tank or tanks of a motor vehicle, and such other information as the director may require. Such application must also contain, as a condition to the issuance of the license, an agreement by the applicant to comply with the provisions and requirements of this act and the rules and regulations promulgated by the director. If the applicant is a partnership or association, the application shall set forth the name and address of each partner or person constituting the partnership, or association, and if a corporation, the names and addresses of the principal officers thereof, and any other information prescribed by the director for the purposes of identification. The application shall be signed and verified by oath or affirmation by the owner, if a natural person, and in case of partnership or association, by a partner or member thereof, and in case of a corporation, by an executive officer thereof or some person specifically authorized by the corporation to sign the application, to which shall be attached written evidence of such person's authority. Any valid LP-gas user's or LP-gas dealer's license in effect on the effective date of this act shall remain in full force and effect and no new application need be made under this act. (f) In the event that any application for a license to use LP-gas as an LP-gas user or LP-gas dealer in this state shall be filed by any person whose license shall at any time theretofore have been canceled for cause, or in case the director shall be of the opinion that such application is not filed in good faith, or that such application is filed by some person as a subterfuge for the real person in interest whose license or registration shall theretofore have been canceled for cause, then and in any of such events, the director may refuse to issue to such person a license in this state. Notice of such refusal shall be mailed to the applicant. Any applicant aggrieved by the order of the director refusing to issue a license may request a hearing of the director on such application by filing with the director a written request therefor. Upon such filing the director shall conduct a hearing in accordance with the provisions of the Kansas administrative procedure act. If the director finds upon such hearing that [the] applicant is entitled to a license, the director shall order its issuance, but if the director finds that such applicant is not entitled to a license, such director shall enter an order refusing issuance. (g) Upon the filing of the application for a license, a filing fee of $5 shall be paid to the director. All such fees collected by the director shall be remitted to the state treasurer in accordance with the provisions of K.S.A. 75-4215, and amendments thereto. Upon receipt of each such remittance, the state treasurer shall deposit the entire amount in the state treasury to the credit of the state general fund. The application in proper form having been accepted for filing, the bond hereafter provided for having been accepted and approved by the director and the other conditions and requirements of this act having been complied with, the director shall issue to such applicant a license and such license shall be in force so long as the holder thereof has in force a bond as required by this act deposited with the director, or until such license is suspended, surrendered, or revoked for cause by the director. The license issued by the director shall not be assignable and shall be valid only for the LP-gas user or LP-gas dealer in whose name issued, and shall be displayed conspicuously by the LP-gas user or LP-gas dealer at the user's or dealer's principal place of business as set forth in the application. (h) In the event a person qualifies for both a user's and dealer's license, only one license shall be required. A copy of such user's or dealer's license shall be required for each place of business of the licensee where LP-gas is sold or dispensed. No charge shall be made for additional copies of such user's or dealer's license when such copies are required for multiple business locations.</p>
            </content>
            <subsection eId="79_3495__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Each LP-gas user or LP-gas dealer subject to the provisions of this act must, on or before the 25 th day of each calendar month, file with the director a report, certified to be true and correct, on a form prescribed and furnished by the director, showing the total number of gallons of LP-gas placed into fuel supply tank or tanks of any motor vehicle while such vehicle is within this state during the preceding calendar month, including the number of gallons on hand at the beginning and end of each month, the number of gallons received from any and all sources supported by detailed schedules of receipts, purchases and withdrawals for sale or use, and such other information as the director may require. Each LP-gas user or LP-gas dealer at the time of filing each monthly report must pay to the director the full amount of tax due for the preceding calendar month at the rate provided for in this act.</p>
              </content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_3495__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Any tax imposed under the provisions of this act not paid on or before the 25 th of the month succeeding the calendar month in which the LP-gas was used shall be deemed delinquent and shall bear interest at the rate per month, or fraction thereof prescribed by subsection</p>
              </content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_3495__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of K.S.A. 79-2968, and amendments thereto, from such due date until paid, and in addition thereto there is hereby imposed upon all amounts of such tax remaining due and unpaid after such due date a penalty in the amount of 5% thereof, and such penalty shall be by the director added to and collected as a part of such tax. If the LP-gas user or LP-gas dealer furnishes evidence to the director that the delinquency was due to causes beyond such user's or dealer's reasonable control, and if in the opinion of the director the delinquency was not the result of willful negligence of the LP-gas user or LP-gas dealer the penalty or interest or both may be waived or reduced by the director.</p>
              </content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_3495__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The director, if satisfied that the enforcement of the act is not adversely affected, may exempt any LP-gas user or LP-gas dealer from the monthly reporting and payment requirements of this act and require in lieu thereof annual payment of the tax due hereunder and annual reporting on forms provided by the director.</p>
              </content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_3495__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Whenever the secretary or the secretary's designee determines that the failure of the taxpayer to comply with the provisions of subsection</p>
              </content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_3495__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>was due to reasonable causes, the secretary or the secretary's designee may waive or reduce any of the penalties and may reduce the interest rate to the underpayment rate prescribed and determined for the applicable period under section 6621 of the federal internal revenue code as in effect on January 1, 1994, upon making a record of the reasons therefor.</p>
              </content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_3495__subsec_e">
              <num>(e)</num>
              <content>
                <p>It shall be unlawful for any LP-gas user or LP-gas dealer to use or sell any LP-gas within this state unless such LP-gas user or LP-gas dealer is a holder of an uncanceled, unsuspended or unrevoked license issued by the director, unless such user has remitted the tax to a licensed LP-gas dealer. To procure such license every applicant shall file with the director an application upon oath and in such form as the director may prescribe, setting forth the name and addresses, the kind of business, and the designation of the exact locations or places of business where LP-gas is delivered or placed into the fuel supply tank or tanks of a motor vehicle, and such other information as the director may require. Such application must also contain, as a condition to the issuance of the license, an agreement by the applicant to comply with the provisions and requirements of this act and the rules and regulations promulgated by the director. If the applicant is a partnership or association, the application shall set forth the name and address of each partner or person constituting the partnership, or association, and if a corporation, the names and addresses of the principal officers thereof, and any other information prescribed by the director for the purposes of identification. The application shall be signed and verified by oath or affirmation by the owner, if a natural person, and in case of partnership or association, by a partner or member thereof, and in case of a corporation, by an executive officer thereof or some person specifically authorized by the corporation to sign the application, to which shall be attached written evidence of such person's authority. Any valid LP-gas user's or LP-gas dealer's license in effect on the effective date of this act shall remain in full force and effect and no new application need be made under this act.</p>
              </content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_3495__subsec_f">
              <num>(f)</num>
              <content>
                <p>In the event that any application for a license to use LP-gas as an LP-gas user or LP-gas dealer in this state shall be filed by any person whose license shall at any time theretofore have been canceled for cause, or in case the director shall be of the opinion that such application is not filed in good faith, or that such application is filed by some person as a subterfuge for the real person in interest whose license or registration shall theretofore have been canceled for cause, then and in any of such events, the director may refuse to issue to such person a license in this state. Notice of such refusal shall be mailed to the applicant. Any applicant aggrieved by the order of the director refusing to issue a license may request a hearing of the director on such application by filing with the director a written request therefor. Upon such filing the director shall conduct a hearing in accordance with the provisions of the Kansas administrative procedure act. If the director finds upon such hearing that [the] applicant is entitled to a license, the director shall order its issuance, but if the director finds that such applicant is not entitled to a license, such director shall enter an order refusing issuance.</p>
              </content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_3495__subsec_g">
              <num>(g)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Upon the filing of the application for a license, a filing fee of $5 shall be paid to the director. All such fees collected by the director shall be remitted to the state treasurer in accordance with the provisions of K.S.A. 75-4215, and amendments thereto. Upon receipt of each such remittance, the state treasurer shall deposit the entire amount in the state treasury to the credit of the state general fund. The application in proper form having been accepted for filing, the bond hereafter provided for having been accepted and approved by the director and the other conditions and requirements of this act having been complied with, the director shall issue to such applicant a license and such license shall be in force so long as the holder thereof has in force a bond as required by this act deposited with the director, or until such license is suspended, surrendered, or revoked for cause by the director. The license issued by the director shall not be assignable and shall be valid only for the LP-gas user or LP-gas dealer in whose name issued, and shall be displayed conspicuously by the LP-gas user or LP-gas dealer at the user's or dealer's principal place of business as set forth in the application.</p>
              </content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_3495__subsec_h">
              <num>(h)</num>
              <content>
                <p>In the event a person qualifies for both a user's and dealer's license, only one license shall be required. A copy of such user's or dealer's license shall be required for each place of business of the licensee where LP-gas is sold or dispensed. No charge shall be made for additional copies of such user's or dealer's license when such copies are required for multiple business locations.</p>
              </content>
            </subsection>
          </section>
        </article>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
