<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ks-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-1496"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-1496"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ks-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ks"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-1496/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-1496/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ks-legislature"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-1496/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-1496/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ks-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ks/legislature" showAs="Kansas Legislature"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_79">
        <num>Chapter 79</num>
        <heading>Taxation</heading>
        <article eId="chp_79__art_14">
          <num>Article 14</num>
          <heading>Property Valuation, Equalizing Assessments, Appraisers and Assessment of Property</heading>
          <section eId="sec_79_1496">
            <num>79-1496</num>
            <heading>Appeals by taxpayers from classification or valuation of property; third-party fee simple appraisals; duties of county appraiser; appeals to state board of tax appeals</heading>
            <content>
              <p>79-1496. Appeals by taxpayers from classification or valuation of property; third-party fee simple appraisals; duties of county appraiser; appeals to state board of tax appeals. Within 60 days after the date the notice of informal meeting results or final determination is mailed to the taxpayer pursuant to K.S.A. 79-1448, and amendments thereto, any taxpayer aggrieved by the final determination of the county appraiser, who has not filed an appeal with the board of tax appeals pursuant to K.S.A. 74-2433f, 79-1448, 79-1609 or 79-1611, and amendments thereto, may file with the county appraiser a third-party fee simple appraisal performed by a Kansas certified general real property appraiser that reflects the value of the property as of January 1 for the same tax year being appealed. For determinations and appeals relating to residential property pursuant to this section, a taxpayer may file with the county appraiser a third-party fee simple appraisal performed by either a Kansas certified residential real property appraiser or a Kansas certified general real property appraiser that reflects the value of the property as of January 1 for the same tax year being appealed. Within 15 days after receipt of the appraisal, the county appraiser shall review and consider such appraisal in the determination of valuation or classification of the taxpayer's property and mail a supplemental notice of final determination. If the final determination is not in favor of the taxpayer then the county appraiser shall notify the taxpayer that the county is required to perform its own, or commission a fee simple single property appraisal. The county appraiser shall then have 90 days to furnish that appraisal along with a new supplemental notice of determination and if not in favor of the taxpayer include an explanation of the reasons the county appraiser did not rely upon the taxpayer's fee simple single property appraisal. Whenever a taxpayer submits a fee simple single property appraisal the burden of proof shall be on the county appraiser to dispute the value of that appraisal. Any taxpayer aggrieved by the final determination of the county appraiser may appeal to the state board of tax appeals as provided in K.S.A. 79-1609, and amendments thereto, within 30 days subsequent to the date of mailing of the supplemental notice of final determination.</p>
            </content>
          </section>
        </article>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
