<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ks-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-3221"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-3221"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ks-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ks"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-3221/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-3221/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ks-legislature"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-3221/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-3221/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ks-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ks/legislature" showAs="Kansas Legislature"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_79">
        <num>Chapter 79</num>
        <heading>Taxation</heading>
        <article eId="chp_79__art_32">
          <num>Article 32</num>
          <heading>Income Tax</heading>
          <section eId="sec_79_3221">
            <num>79-3221</num>
            <heading>Returns; form, place and time of filing; identifying number, social security numbers; tentative returns; extension of time; certain actions or proceedings authorized; definitions</heading>
            <content>
              <p>79-3221. Returns; form, place and time of filing; identifying number, social security numbers; tentative returns; extension of time; certain actions or proceedings authorized; definitions. (a) All returns required by this act shall be made as nearly as practical in the same form as the corresponding form of income tax return by the United States. Unless another identifying number has been assigned to an individual by the internal revenue service for purposes of filing such individual's federal income tax return, the social security number issued to an individual, the individual's spouse, and all dependents of such individual for purposes of section 205(c)(2)(A) of the social security act shall be used as the identifying number and included on the return when filing such return. (b) All returns shall be filed in the office of the director of taxation on or before the 15 th day of the fourth month following the close of the taxable year, except as provided in subsection (c). Tentative returns may be filed before the close of the taxable year and the estimated tax computed on such return, paid, but no interest will be paid on any overpayment of tax liability, computed on such tentative return. (c) (1) The director of taxation may grant a reasonable extension of time for filing returns in accordance with rules and regulations of the secretary of revenue. Whenever any such extension of time to file is requested by a taxpayer and granted by the director with respect to any tax year commencing after December 31, 1992, no penalty authorized by K.S.A. 79-3228, and amendments thereto, shall be imposed if 90% of the liability is paid on or before the original due date. (2) For any tax year commencing after December 31, 2019, any taxpayer filing a corporate tax return shall file the return in the office of the director of taxation: (A) No later than one month after the due date established under the federal internal revenue code, including any applicable extensions granted by the internal revenue service; and (B) no penalty authorized by K.S.A. 79-3228, and amendments thereto, shall be imposed if the return is filed within one month after receiving an extension to file a tax return with the internal revenue service. The taxpayer shall not be required to file an extension request with the director pursuant to this subparagraph. (3) For any tax year commencing after December 31, 2019, any taxpayer filing a return, other than a corporate tax return, shall file the return in the office of the director of taxation not later than the due date established under the federal internal revenue code, including any applicable extensions granted by the internal revenue service. No penalty authorized by K.S.A. 79-3228, and amendments thereto, shall be imposed if the return is filed not later than the deadline established by the internal revenue service. The taxpayer shall not be required to file an extension request with the director pursuant to this paragraph. (d) In the case of an individual serving in the armed forces of the United States, or serving in support of such armed forces, in an area designated by the president of the United States by executive order as a &quot;combat zone&quot; as defined under 26 U.S.C. § 112 at any time during the period designated by the president by executive order as the period of combatant activities in such zone for the purposes of such section, or hospitalized as a result of injury received or sickness incurred while serving in such an area during such time, the period of service in such area, plus the period of continuous qualified hospitalization attributable to such injury or sickness, and the next 180 days thereafter, shall be disregarded in determining, under article 32 of chapter 79 of the Kansas Statutes Annotated, and amendments thereto, in respect to any tax liability, including any interest, penalty, additional amount, or addition to the tax, of such individual: (1) Whether any of the following acts was performed within the time prescribed therefor: (A) Filing any return of income tax; (B) payment of any income tax or installment thereof; (C) filing a notice of appeal with the director of taxation or the state board of tax appeals for redetermination of a deficiency or for a review of a decision rendered by either the director or the state board of tax appeals; (D) allowance of a credit or refund of any income tax; (E) filing a claim for credit or refund of any income tax; (F) bringing suit upon any such claim for credit or refund; (G) assessment of any income tax; (H) giving or making any notice or demand for the payment of any income tax, or with respect to any liability to the state of Kansas in respect of any income tax; (I) collection, by the director of taxation or the director's agent, by warrant, levy or otherwise, of the amount of any liability in respect to any income tax; (J) bringing suit by the state of Kansas, or any officer on its behalf, in respect to any liability in respect of any income tax; and (K) any other act required or permitted under the Kansas income tax act specified in rules and regulations adopted by the secretary of revenue under this section; (2) the amount of any credit or refund. (e) (1) Subsection (d) shall not apply for purposes of determining the amount of interest on any overpayment of tax. (2) If an individual is entitled to the benefits of subsection (d) with respect to any return and such return is timely filed, determined after the application of subsection (d), K.S.A. 79-32,105(e)(5) and (e)(7), and amendments thereto, shall not apply. (f) The provisions of subsections (d) through (j) shall apply to the spouse of any individual entitled to the benefits of subsection (d). Except in the case of the combat zone designated for purposes of the Vietnam conflict, this subsection shall not cause subsections (d) through (j) to apply for any spouse for any taxable year beginning more than two years after the date designated under 26 U.S.C. § 112, and amendments thereto, as the date of termination of combatant activities in a combat zone. (g) The period of service in the area referred to in subsection (d) shall include the period during which an individual entitled to benefits under subsection (d) is in a missing status, within the meaning of 26 U.S.C. § 6013(f)(3). (h) (1) Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (d), any action or proceeding authorized by K.S.A. 79-3229, and amendments thereto, as well as any other action or proceeding authorized by law in connection therewith, may be taken, begun or prosecuted. In any other case in which the secretary determines that collection of the amount of any assessment would be jeopardized by delay, the provisions of subsection (d) shall not operate to stay collection of such amount by levy or otherwise as authorized by law. There shall be excluded from any amount assessed or collected pursuant to this subsection the amount of interest, penalty, additional amount, and addition to the tax, if any, in respect of the period disregarded under subsection (d). In any case to which this subsection relates, if the secretary is required to give any notice to or make any demand upon any person, such requirement shall be deemed to be satisfied if the notice or demand is prepared and signed, in any case in which the address of such person last known to the secretary is in an area for which United States post offices under instructions of the postmaster general are not, by reason of the combatant activities, accepting mail for delivery at the time the notice or demand is signed. In such case the notice or demand shall be deemed to have been given or made upon the date it is signed. (2) The assessment or collection of any tax under the provisions of article 32 of chapter 79 of the Kansas Statutes Annotated, and amendments thereto, or any action or proceeding by or on behalf of the state in connection therewith, may be made, taken, begun or prosecuted in accordance with law, without regard to the provisions of subsection (d), unless prior to such assessment, collection, action or proceeding it is ascertained that the person concerned is entitled to the benefits of subsection (d). (i) (1) Any individual who performed Desert Shield services, and the spouse of such individual, shall be entitled to the benefits of subsections (d) through (j) in the same manner as if such services were services referred to in subsection (d). (2) For purposes of this subsection, the term &quot;Desert Shield services&quot; means any services in the armed forces of the United States or in support of such armed forces if: (A) Such services are performed in the area designated by the president as the &quot;Persian Gulf Desert Shield area&quot;; and (B) such services are performed during the period beginning on August 2, 1990, and ending on the date on which any portion of the area referred to in subsection (i)(2)(A) is designated by the president as a combat zone pursuant to 26 U.S.C. § 112. (j) For purposes of subsection (d), the term &quot;qualified hospitalization&quot; means: (1) Any hospitalization outside the United States; and (2) any hospitalization inside the United States, except that not more than five years of hospitalization may be taken into account under this subsection. This subsection shall not apply for purposes of applying subsections (d) through (j) with respect to the spouse of an individual entitled to the benefits of subsection (d).</p>
            </content>
            <subsection eId="79_3221__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>All returns required by this act shall be made as nearly as practical in the same form as the corresponding form of income tax return by the United States. Unless another identifying number has been assigned to an individual by the internal revenue service for purposes of filing such individual's federal income tax return, the social security number issued to an individual, the individual's spouse, and all dependents of such individual for purposes of section 205</p>
              </content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_3221__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>All returns shall be filed in the office of the director of taxation on or before the 15 th day of the fourth month following the close of the taxable year, except as provided in subsection</p>
              </content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_3221__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <paragraph eId="79_3221__subsec_c__para_1">
                <num>(1)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>The director of taxation may grant a reasonable extension of time for filing returns in accordance with rules and regulations of the secretary of revenue. Whenever any such extension of time to file is requested by a taxpayer and granted by the director with respect to any tax year commencing after December 31, 1992, no penalty authorized by K.S.A. 79-3228, and amendments thereto, shall be imposed if 90% of the liability is paid on or before the original due date.</p>
                </content>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph eId="79_3221__subsec_c__para_2">
                <num>(2)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>For any tax year commencing after December 31, 2019, any taxpayer filing a corporate tax return shall file the return in the office of the director of taxation: (A) No later than one month after the due date established under the federal internal revenue code, including any applicable extensions granted by the internal revenue service; and (B) no penalty authorized by K.S.A. 79-3228, and amendments thereto, shall be imposed if the return is filed within one month after receiving an extension to file a tax return with the internal revenue service. The taxpayer shall not be required to file an extension request with the director pursuant to this subparagraph.</p>
                </content>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph eId="79_3221__subsec_c__para_3">
                <num>(3)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>For any tax year commencing after December 31, 2019, any taxpayer filing a return, other than a corporate tax return, shall file the return in the office of the director of taxation not later than the due date established under the federal internal revenue code, including any applicable extensions granted by the internal revenue service. No penalty authorized by K.S.A. 79-3228, and amendments thereto, shall be imposed if the return is filed not later than the deadline established by the internal revenue service. The taxpayer shall not be required to file an extension request with the director pursuant to this paragraph.</p>
                </content>
              </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_3221__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>In the case of an individual serving in the armed forces of the United States, or serving in support of such armed forces, in an area designated by the president of the United States by executive order as a &quot;combat zone&quot; as defined under 26 U.S.C. § 112 at any time during the period designated by the president by executive order as the period of combatant activities in such zone for the purposes of such section, or hospitalized as a result of injury received or sickness incurred while serving in such an area during such time, the period of service in such area, plus the period of continuous qualified hospitalization attributable to such injury or sickness, and the next 180 days thereafter, shall be disregarded in determining, under article 32 of chapter 79 of the Kansas Statutes Annotated, and amendments thereto, in respect to any tax liability, including any interest, penalty, additional amount, or addition to the tax, of such individual:</p>
              </content>
              <paragraph eId="79_3221__subsec_d__para_1">
                <num>(1)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Whether any of the following acts was performed within the time prescribed therefor: (A) Filing any return of income tax; (B) payment of any income tax or installment thereof; (C) filing a notice of appeal with the director of taxation or the state board of tax appeals for redetermination of a deficiency or for a review of a decision rendered by either the director or the state board of tax appeals; (D) allowance of a credit or refund of any income tax; (E) filing a claim for credit or refund of any income tax; (F) bringing suit upon any such claim for credit or refund; (G) assessment of any income tax; (H) giving or making any notice or demand for the payment of any income tax, or with respect to any liability to the state of Kansas in respect of any income tax; (I) collection, by the director of taxation or the director's agent, by warrant, levy or otherwise, of the amount of any liability in respect to any income tax; (J) bringing suit by the state of Kansas, or any officer on its behalf, in respect to any liability in respect of any income tax; and (K) any other act required or permitted under the Kansas income tax act specified in rules and regulations adopted by the secretary of revenue under this section;</p>
                </content>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph eId="79_3221__subsec_d__para_2">
                <num>(2)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>the amount of any credit or refund.</p>
                </content>
              </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_3221__subsec_e">
              <num>(e)</num>
              <paragraph eId="79_3221__subsec_e__para_1">
                <num>(1)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Subsection</p>
                </content>
              </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_3221__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>shall not apply for purposes of determining the amount of interest on any overpayment of tax.</p>
              </content>
              <paragraph eId="79_3221__subsec_d__para_2">
                <num>(2)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>If an individual is entitled to the benefits of subsection</p>
                </content>
              </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_3221__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>with respect to any return and such return is timely filed, determined after the application of subsection</p>
              </content>
              <paragraph eId="79_3221__subsec_d__para_5">
                <num>(5)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>and</p>
                </content>
              </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_3221__subsec_f">
              <num>(f)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The provisions of subsections</p>
              </content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_3221__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>through</p>
              </content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_3221__subsec_j">
              <num>(j)</num>
              <content>
                <p>shall apply to the spouse of any individual entitled to the benefits of subsection</p>
              </content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_3221__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>through</p>
              </content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_3221__subsec_j">
              <num>(j)</num>
              <content>
                <p>to apply for any spouse for any taxable year beginning more than two years after the date designated under 26 U.S.C. § 112, and amendments thereto, as the date of termination of combatant activities in a combat zone.</p>
              </content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_3221__subsec_g">
              <num>(g)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The period of service in the area referred to in subsection</p>
              </content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_3221__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>shall include the period during which an individual entitled to benefits under subsection</p>
              </content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_3221__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>is in a missing status, within the meaning of 26 U.S.C. § 6013</p>
              </content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_3221__subsec_h">
              <num>(h)</num>
              <paragraph eId="79_3221__subsec_h__para_1">
                <num>(1)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection</p>
                </content>
              </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_3221__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>shall not operate to stay collection of such amount by levy or otherwise as authorized by law. There shall be excluded from any amount assessed or collected pursuant to this subsection the amount of interest, penalty, additional amount, and addition to the tax, if any, in respect of the period disregarded under subsection</p>
              </content>
              <paragraph eId="79_3221__subsec_d__para_2">
                <num>(2)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>The assessment or collection of any tax under the provisions of article 32 of chapter 79 of the Kansas Statutes Annotated, and amendments thereto, or any action or proceeding by or on behalf of the state in connection therewith, may be made, taken, begun or prosecuted in accordance with law, without regard to the provisions of subsection</p>
                </content>
              </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_3221__subsec_i">
              <num>(i)</num>
              <paragraph eId="79_3221__subsec_i__para_1">
                <num>(1)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Any individual who performed Desert Shield services, and the spouse of such individual, shall be entitled to the benefits of subsections</p>
                </content>
              </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_3221__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>through</p>
              </content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_3221__subsec_j">
              <num>(j)</num>
              <content>
                <p>in the same manner as if such services were services referred to in subsection</p>
              </content>
              <paragraph eId="79_3221__subsec_j__para_2">
                <num>(2)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>For purposes of this subsection, the term &quot;Desert Shield services&quot; means any services in the armed forces of the United States or in support of such armed forces if: (A) Such services are performed in the area designated by the president as the &quot;Persian Gulf Desert Shield area&quot;; and (B) such services are performed during the period beginning on August 2, 1990, and ending on the date on which any portion of the area referred to in subsection</p>
                </content>
              </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_3221__subsec_j">
              <num>(j)</num>
              <content>
                <p>For purposes of subsection</p>
              </content>
              <paragraph eId="79_3221__subsec_j__para_1">
                <num>(1)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Any hospitalization outside the United States; and</p>
                </content>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph eId="79_3221__subsec_j__para_2">
                <num>(2)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>any hospitalization inside the United States, except that not more than five years of hospitalization may be taken into account under this subsection. This subsection shall not apply for purposes of applying subsections</p>
                </content>
              </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_3221__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>through</p>
              </content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_3221__subsec_j">
              <num>(j)</num>
              <content>
                <p>with respect to the spouse of an individual entitled to the benefits of subsection</p>
              </content>
            </subsection>
          </section>
        </article>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
