<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ks-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-3220"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-3220"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ks-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ks"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-3220/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-3220/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ks-legislature"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-3220/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-3220/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ks-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ks/legislature" showAs="Kansas Legislature"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_79">
        <num>Chapter 79</num>
        <heading>Taxation</heading>
        <article eId="chp_79__art_32">
          <num>Article 32</num>
          <heading>Income Tax</heading>
          <section eId="sec_79_3220">
            <num>79-3220</num>
            <heading>Requirements for individuals, corporations, fiduciaries and partnerships with regard to returns</heading>
            <content>
              <p>79-3220. Requirements for individuals, corporations, fiduciaries and partnerships with regard to returns. (a) (1) Each individual required to file a federal income tax return and any other individual whose gross income exceeds the sum of such individual's applicable Kansas standard deduction amount and Kansas personal exemption amount shall each make and sign a return or statement stating specifically such items as are required by the forms and rules and regulations of the secretary of revenue. If any individual is unable to make a return, the return shall be made by a duly authorized agent or by the guardian or other person charged with the care of the person or property of such taxpayer. Notwithstanding any provision of the Kansas income tax act to the contrary, all individuals not required to file a Kansas income tax return hereunder shall not be liable for any tax imposed pursuant to such act. (2) In accordance with the provisions of K.S.A. 75-5151a, and amendments thereto, an individual who is required to file a return may file such return by electronic means in a manner approved by the secretary of revenue. A paid preparer who prepares 50 or more returns per year shall file by electronic means not less than 90% of such returns eligible for electronic filing. The requirements of this subsection may be waived by the secretary of revenue for a paid preparer if the paid preparer demonstrates a hardship in complying with the requirements of this subsection. (3) For purposes of this subsection, a nonresident individual or fiduciary whose only source of income from this state is income from an electing pass-through entity under the salt parity act shall not be required to file a return. (b) Every corporation subject to taxation under this act, including, but not limited to, all farmers, fruit growers, or like associations organized and operated on a cooperative basis, except electric cooperative exclusively engaged in the manufacture or distribution of electric power for their members, shall make a return, or statement stating specifically such items as may be required by the forms and regulations of the secretary of revenue. The return shall be signed by the president, vice-president, treasurer, assistant treasurer, chief accounting officer or any other officer so authorized to act. The fact that an individual's name is signed on a return shall be prima facie evidence that such individual is authorized to sign such return on behalf of such corporation. In cases where receivers, trustees in bankruptcy or assignees are operating the property or business of corporations, such receivers, trustees, or assignees shall make returns for such corporations in the same manner and form as corporations are required to make returns. Any tax due on the basis of such returns shall be collected in the same manner as if collected from the corporation for which the return is made. (c) Every fiduciary, except a receiver appointed by authority of law in possession of part only of the property of an individual shall make and sign a return for each of the individuals, estates, or trusts for which the fiduciary acts, when such returns are required by the provisions of this act, stating specifically such items as may be required by the forms and regulations of the secretary of revenue. In the case of joint fiduciaries, whether residents or nonresidents, a return may be made by any one and shall be sufficient compliance with the above requirements. Any fiduciary required to make a return under this act shall be subject to all of the provisions of law which apply to individuals. (d) Every partnership shall make a return for each taxable year, stating specifically such items as may be required by the forms and regulations of the secretary of revenue. The returns shall be signed by any one of the partners.</p>
            </content>
            <subsection eId="79_3220__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <paragraph eId="79_3220__subsec_a__para_1">
                <num>(1)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Each individual required to file a federal income tax return and any other individual whose gross income exceeds the sum of such individual's applicable Kansas standard deduction amount and Kansas personal exemption amount shall each make and sign a return or statement stating specifically such items as are required by the forms and rules and regulations of the secretary of revenue. If any individual is unable to make a return, the return shall be made by a duly authorized agent or by the guardian or other person charged with the care of the person or property of such taxpayer. Notwithstanding any provision of the Kansas income tax act to the contrary, all individuals not required to file a Kansas income tax return hereunder shall not be liable for any tax imposed pursuant to such act.</p>
                </content>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph eId="79_3220__subsec_a__para_2">
                <num>(2)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>In accordance with the provisions of K.S.A. 75-5151a, and amendments thereto, an individual who is required to file a return may file such return by electronic means in a manner approved by the secretary of revenue. A paid preparer who prepares 50 or more returns per year shall file by electronic means not less than 90% of such returns eligible for electronic filing. The requirements of this subsection may be waived by the secretary of revenue for a paid preparer if the paid preparer demonstrates a hardship in complying with the requirements of this subsection.</p>
                </content>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph eId="79_3220__subsec_a__para_3">
                <num>(3)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>For purposes of this subsection, a nonresident individual or fiduciary whose only source of income from this state is income from an electing pass-through entity under the salt parity act shall not be required to file a return.</p>
                </content>
              </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_3220__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Every corporation subject to taxation under this act, including, but not limited to, all farmers, fruit growers, or like associations organized and operated on a cooperative basis, except electric cooperative exclusively engaged in the manufacture or distribution of electric power for their members, shall make a return, or statement stating specifically such items as may be required by the forms and regulations of the secretary of revenue. The return shall be signed by the president, vice-president, treasurer, assistant treasurer, chief accounting officer or any other officer so authorized to act. The fact that an individual's name is signed on a return shall be prima facie evidence that such individual is authorized to sign such return on behalf of such corporation. In cases where receivers, trustees in bankruptcy or assignees are operating the property or business of corporations, such receivers, trustees, or assignees shall make returns for such corporations in the same manner and form as corporations are required to make returns. Any tax due on the basis of such returns shall be collected in the same manner as if collected from the corporation for which the return is made.</p>
              </content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_3220__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Every fiduciary, except a receiver appointed by authority of law in possession of part only of the property of an individual shall make and sign a return for each of the individuals, estates, or trusts for which the fiduciary acts, when such returns are required by the provisions of this act, stating specifically such items as may be required by the forms and regulations of the secretary of revenue. In the case of joint fiduciaries, whether residents or nonresidents, a return may be made by any one and shall be sufficient compliance with the above requirements. Any fiduciary required to make a return under this act shall be subject to all of the provisions of law which apply to individuals.</p>
              </content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_3220__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Every partnership shall make a return for each taxable year, stating specifically such items as may be required by the forms and regulations of the secretary of revenue. The returns shall be signed by any one of the partners.</p>
              </content>
            </subsection>
          </section>
        </article>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
