<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ks-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-401"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-401"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ks-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ks"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-401/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-401/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ks-legislature"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-401/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-401/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ks-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ks/legislature" showAs="Kansas Legislature"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_79">
        <num>Chapter 79</num>
        <heading>Taxation</heading>
        <article eId="chp_79__art_4">
          <num>Article 4</num>
          <heading>Listing and Valuation of Real Estate</heading>
          <section eId="sec_79_401">
            <num>79-401</num>
            <heading>Section 79-401</heading>
            <content>
              <p>2023-2024
Legislative Sessions
Return to current session
Home •
News •
Contact •
House
Leadership
Committees
Rules
Current Events
Seating Chart
Roster
Chief Clerk of the House
Senate
Leadership
Committees
Confirmations
Rules
Current Events
Seating Chart
Roster
Secretary of the Senate
Legislators
House Leadership
House Roster
Senate Leadership
Senate Roster
Committees
Committees
Standing
Joint
Special and Select
Commission
Subcommittee
Task Force
Other
Conference Schedules
Conference Committees
Committee Bill Hearings
Bills &amp; Laws
Senate Bills
House Bills
Statute
Reports
Actions and Subject Index Report
How a bill becomes law (pdf)
Kansas Constitution
Contact the Revisor
Journals
House Journal
Senate Journal
What is a Journal?
Calendars
House Calendar
Senate Calendar
What Is A Calendar?
Research
Memos/Reports/Publications
Appropriations
Revenue/Taxation
Redistricting
About KLRD
Historical
2025-26 Regular Sessions
2024 Special Session
2021-2022 Regular Sessions
2021 Special Session
2020 Special Session
2019-2020 Regular Sessions
2017-2018 Regular Sessions
2016 Special Session
2015-2016 Regular Sessions
2013-2014 Regular Sessions
2013 Special Session
2011-2012 Regular Sessions
1997 - 2010 Sessions
2000 - 2010 Committee Data
Find Bill
Bill/Resolution Lookup:
Find Your Legislator
Chamber:
Both Chambers
Senate
House
Party:
All Parties
Republican
Democrat
Search by Your Address
Legislative Deadlines
Senate Deadlines
(PDF)
House Deadlines
(PDF)
Current Events
Statute
Legislative Resources
Administrative Services
Division of Post Audit
Information Services
Research Department
Revisor of Statutes
LCC Policies
About the Legislature
Other State Resources
Kansas.gov
Ethics Commission
How Do I…
Become A Legislative Intern
Become A Legislative Page
Apply For Session Work
Dec. 31, 2025
-A
+A
House Status:
Adjourned until Monday, January 13, 2025 at 02:00 p.m.
Senate Status:
Adjourned until Monday, January 13, 2025 at 02:00 p.m.
you are here:
Home
»
Statute
»
Chapter 79
»
Article 40
»
Section 1
»
2024
 Statute
Prev
Article 40. - MUNICIPAL TAX LEVIES
Next
79-4001.
General improvements for library purposes; tax levy, use of proceeds; election required.
Any municipality, as the same is defined in K.S.A. 10-1101, is hereby authorized to make an annual tax levy not to exceed two mills for the purpose of creating and providing a special fund to be used in making any general improvement which such municipality is authorized by law to make, or, to be used to remodel, construct, reconstruct, furnish and equip an addition or annex to any library being operated and maintained by such municipality, and in the case of cities, counties and school districts, to pay a portion of the principal and interest on bonds issued by cities under the authority of K.S.A. 12-1774, and amendments thereto, for the financing of redevelopment projects upon property located in such county or such school district. The governing body of such municipalities shall by resolution submit the question of making such levy to the qualified electors of the municipality at any general election or at a special election called for such purpose. The question as stated on the ballot shall show the nature of the improvement contemplated, the total amount to be raised by taxes, and the period over which such levy is to be made, which shall in no case exceed ten (10) years. If a majority of those voting on such proposition vote in favor thereof, the governing body shall make said levy and create such fund, the principal and interest thereof to be used for the purpose authorized. Such levy shall be in addition to all other levies authorized by law and none of the limitations of article 19 of chapter 79 of the Kansas Statutes Annotated, or acts amendatory thereof or supplemental thereto, shall apply to such levy. Whenever tax levies have been approved and the fund created as provided for in this section in any city, and thereafter, it becomes evident that the city will be unable to use the fund for the specific purposes herein provided for because of urban renewal plans approved by the federal government providing for the removal of the library building, the governing board of such city shall be and is hereby authorized to use such fund so accumulated for the purposes of purchasing and improving a library or sites, constructing, furnishing, equipping, remodeling or making additions to library buildings, and may continue to make the tax levy for the purposes hereinbefore specified for the period provided, but not to exceed a total of ten (10) years in any case; and said governing board is further authorized to use such funds derived from tax levies to prepay rent under leases with a public building commission as provided for under K.S.A. 12-1757 et seq., and acts amendatory thereof.
History:
L. 1949, ch. 490, § 1; L. 1955, ch. 426, § 1; L. 1968, ch. 171, § 1; L. 1979, ch. 52, § 198; July 1.
Prev
Article 40. - MUNICIPAL TAX LEVIES
Next
2025. Powered by KLISS. Rendered: 2025-12-31T11:43:23. Head Rev No: 1485844(I)</p>
            </content>
          </section>
        </article>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
