<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ks-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-3313"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-3313"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ks-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ks"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-3313/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-3313/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ks-legislature"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-3313/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-3313/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ks-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ks/legislature" showAs="Kansas Legislature"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_79">
        <num>Chapter 79</num>
        <heading>Taxation</heading>
        <article eId="chp_79__art_33">
          <num>Article 33</num>
          <heading>Cigarettes and Tobacco Products</heading>
          <section eId="sec_79_3313">
            <num>79-3313</num>
            <heading>Cigarettes required to be sold in packages; distribution of free sample packages; violations and sanctions; hearing</heading>
            <content>
              <p>79-3313. Cigarettes required to be sold in packages; distribution of free sample packages; violations and sanctions; hearing. All cigarettes sold in this state shall be in packages, and each of the packages shall bear evidence of payment of the tax thereon except that any railroad or sleeping car company licensed as a retailer is hereby authorized to sell cigarettes upon its cars without affixing stamps to the packages of cigarettes provided that monthly reports and payment of the tax due is made directly to the director in the manner and under the terms provided for by the director. In addition, manufacturers are hereby authorized to distribute in the state, through their authorized representatives or wholesale dealers, free sample packages of cigarettes containing less than 20 cigarettes without affixing stamps to the packages provided that monthly reports and payment of a tax at the rates prescribed by law are made directly to the director. No wholesale dealer or manufacturers' authorized representatives shall sell or distribute cigarettes, except free sample packages, to any person in the state of Kansas not holding a dealer's license as provided in this act. Such packages of sample cigarettes shall bear the word &quot;sample&quot; or &quot;not for sale&quot; and &quot;state tax paid&quot; in letters easily read. Whenever the director shall have reason to believe that any manufacturer has violated the provisions of this section or the conditions provided by the director, the director shall conduct a hearing thereon in accordance with the provisions of the Kansas administrative procedure act. If upon the basis of such hearing it appears to the satisfaction of the director that such manufacturer has violated any of the provisions of this section or the conditions provided by the director, the director is hereby authorized to suspend or revoke the authorization to the manufacturer for such period as the director determines is necessary but in no case for more than one year.</p>
            </content>
          </section>
        </article>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
