<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ks-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-3393"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-3393"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ks-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ks"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-3393/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-3393/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ks-legislature"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-3393/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ks/act/ksa/79-3393/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ks-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ks/legislature" showAs="Kansas Legislature"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_79">
        <num>Chapter 79</num>
        <heading>Taxation</heading>
        <article eId="chp_79__art_33">
          <num>Article 33</num>
          <heading>Cigarettes and Tobacco Products</heading>
          <section eId="sec_79_3393">
            <num>79-3393</num>
            <heading>Cigarette or tobacco infraction; procedure</heading>
            <content>
              <p>79-3393. Cigarette or tobacco infraction; procedure. (a) When a person is stopped by a law enforcement officer for a cigarette or tobacco infraction, the law enforcement officer shall prepare and deliver to the person a written cigarette or tobacco citation on a form approved by the secretary of revenue or the secretary's designee. The citation shall contain a notice to appear in court, the name and address of the person, the offense or offenses charged, the time and place when and where the person shall appear in court, the signature of the law enforcement officer and any other pertinent information. The time specified in the notice to appear shall be at least five days after the alleged infraction unless the person charged with the infraction demands an earlier hearing. The place specified in the notice to appear shall be before a judge of the district court within the county where the infraction is alleged to have been committed or before a judge of the municipal court where the infraction is alleged to have been committed in a city which has adopted an ordinance which prohibits the same acts. (b) The notice to appear may provide that the person charged with the infraction shall appear in court with a parent or legal guardian and shall provide that the person charged has a right to trial. (c) Acts classified as cigarette or tobacco infractions by K.S.A. 79-3322 (d) , and amendments thereto, shall be classified as ordinance cigarette or tobacco infractions by those cities adopting ordinances prohibiting the same acts. The fine for an ordinance cigarette or tobacco infraction shall be $25.</p>
            </content>
            <subsection eId="79_3393__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>When a person is stopped by a law enforcement officer for a cigarette or tobacco infraction, the law enforcement officer shall prepare and deliver to the person a written cigarette or tobacco citation on a form approved by the secretary of revenue or the secretary's designee. The citation shall contain a notice to appear in court, the name and address of the person, the offense or offenses charged, the time and place when and where the person shall appear in court, the signature of the law enforcement officer and any other pertinent information. The time specified in the notice to appear shall be at least five days after the alleged infraction unless the person charged with the infraction demands an earlier hearing. The place specified in the notice to appear shall be before a judge of the district court within the county where the infraction is alleged to have been committed or before a judge of the municipal court where the infraction is alleged to have been committed in a city which has adopted an ordinance which prohibits the same acts.</p>
              </content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_3393__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The notice to appear may provide that the person charged with the infraction shall appear in court with a parent or legal guardian and shall provide that the person charged has a right to trial.</p>
              </content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_3393__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Acts classified as cigarette or tobacco infractions by K.S.A. 79-3322</p>
              </content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection eId="79_3393__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>, and amendments thereto, shall be classified as ordinance cigarette or tobacco infractions by those cities adopting ordinances prohibiting the same acts. The fine for an ordinance cigarette or tobacco infraction shall be $25.</p>
              </content>
            </subsection>
          </section>
        </article>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
